[{"question":"14) Physics – Short Answer - If the temperature of an ideal gas is quadrupled, by what factor is\nthe speed of sound in that gas multiplied?\n","spokenAnswer":"2\n","answer":"2\n","timer":5},{"question":"12) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following could be the products of anaerobic\nfermentation of glucose?\nW) Ethanol and water\nX) Acetone and water\nY) Ethanol and carbon dioxide\nZ) Acetone and carbon dioxide\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) ETHANOL AND CARBON DIOXIDE\n","answer":"Y) ETHANOL AND CARBON DIOXIDE\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Refracting telescopes have a severe limitation in that\neach wavelength of light is refracted differently, making it impossible to focus on more than one\nwavelength of light at a time. What is this type of optical aberration called?\n","spokenAnswer":"CHROMATIC ABERRATION (ALSO ACCEPT: CHROMATIC DISTORTION,\n","answer":"CHROMATIC ABERRATION (ALSO ACCEPT: CHROMATIC DISTORTION,\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following enzymes is unique to gluconeogenesis\n[gloo-koh-nee-uh-JEN-uh-sis]?\nW) PEP carboxykinase [kahr-bok-si-KY-nays]\nX) Pyruvate kinase [py-ROO-vayt]\nY) Hexokinase [hek-soh-KY-nays]\nZ) Phosphofructokinase [fohs-foh-frook-toh-KY-nays]\n","spokenAnswer":"W) PEP CARBOXYKINASE\n","answer":"W) PEP CARBOXYKINASE\n","timer":20},{"question":"15) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - What is the name for the topography that is created\nthrough extension of crust, producing distinct horsts and grabens?\n","spokenAnswer":"BASIN AND RANGE\n","answer":"BASIN AND RANGE\n","timer":5},{"question":"4) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - In the Meselson-Stahl experiment, the mechanism for DNA\nreplication was investigated using Escherichia coli [e-schuh-ri-KEE-uh koh-LY] as a model. E.\ncoli was grown in medium with heavy nitrogen until all the DNA was labeled with the heavy\nisotope. Then, the E. coli was transferred to fresh medium with lighter nitrogen and the bacteria\nreplicated once. The DNA was extracted from the bacteria using a density gradient to separate\nlight-nitrogen DNA, heavy-nitrogen DNA, and light/heavy mixed DNA to decide whether\nreplication was conservative or semiconservative. Which of the following results was predicted if\nreplication was conservative?\nW) All the DNA would be light\nX) All of the DNA would be an intermediate density\nY) Half of the DNA would be light, and half would be heavy\nZ) Half of the DNA would be intermediate, and half would be light\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) HALF OF THE DNA WOULD BE LIGHT, AND HALF WOULD BE HEAVY\n","answer":"Y) HALF OF THE DNA WOULD BE LIGHT, AND HALF WOULD BE HEAVY\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following clays has the highest cation\n[KAT-eye-uhn] exchange capacity (CEC)?\nW) Kaolinites [KAY-uh-luh-nyts]\nX) Vermiculites [ver-MIK-yoo-lyts]\nY) Chlorides\nZ) Allophanes\n","spokenAnswer":"X) VERMICULITES\n","answer":"X) VERMICULITES\n","timer":5},{"question":"21) BIOLOGY Short Answer - Name the circulatory adaptation found in the legs of ducks and\ngeese that allows them to swim in water that is near freezing and yet not become hypothermic.\n","spokenAnswer":"COUNTERCURRENT EXCHANGER (ACCEPT: COUNTERCURRENT HEAT\n","answer":"COUNTERCURRENT EXCHANGER (ACCEPT: COUNTERCURRENT HEAT\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) ENERGY Multiple Choice - A liquid metal fast reactor (LMFR) is an advanced type of\nnuclear reactor that uses liquid metal as a primary coolant. Of the following metals, which one is\nNOT most commonly used as a primary coolant in LMFRs?\nW) Lithium\nX) Mercury\nY) Lead\nZ) Sodium\n","spokenAnswer":"W) LITHIUM\n","answer":"W) LITHIUM\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) Physics – Multiple Choice - Identify all of the following three statements that are true regarding RLC\ncircuits: 1) A series RLC circuit consists of an inductor, a capacitor, and a resistor connected in series; 2) The\nresonant frequency is defined as the frequency at which input impedance is at a minimum; 3) RLC circuits\ncan be found in wireless radio receivers.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2, AND 3\n","answer":"1, 2, AND 3\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) Physics – Short Answer - The precession of Mercury’s orbit, which cannot be explained via a classical\napproach, is explained by what theory or principle?\n","spokenAnswer":"GENERAL THEORY OF RELATIVITY (ACCEPT: GENERAL RELATIVITY)\n","answer":"GENERAL THEORY OF RELATIVITY (ACCEPT: GENERAL RELATIVITY)\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three events that occurred\nduring the recombination epoch of the Big Bang: 1) Formation of neutral hydrogen; 2) Neutrino\ndecoupling; 3) Star formation.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 ONLY\n","answer":"1 ONLY\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) BIOLOGY Short Answer - What tree is deciduous [di-SIJ-oo-uhs], dioecious [dy-EE-shus],\nand has leaves that do not possess a central vein but do have dichotomous [dy-KOT-uh-muhs]\nvenation?\n","spokenAnswer":"GINKGO BILOBA (ACCEPT: GINKGO, MAIDENHAIR)\n","answer":"GINKGO BILOBA (ACCEPT: GINKGO, MAIDENHAIR)\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) MATH Multiple Choice - Which of the following is correct about the symmetry of even\nfunctions?\nW) They are symmetric about the y-axis\nX) They are symmetric about the x-axis\nY) They are symmetric about the origin\nZ) They do not necessarily have symmetry\n","spokenAnswer":"W) THEY ARE SYMMETRIC ABOUT THE y-AXIS\n","answer":"W) THEY ARE SYMMETRIC ABOUT THE y-AXIS\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Which of the following experiments provided evidence in favor of\nthe wave theory of light?\nW) Young\n's double slit experiment\nX) Michelson-Morley experiment\nY) Robert Millikan\n's oil-drop experiment\nZ) Huygens\n' experiment\n","spokenAnswer":"W) YOUNG\n'S DOUBLE SLIT EXPERIMENT\n","answer":"W) YOUNG\n'S DOUBLE SLIT EXPERIMENT\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) Chemistry – Short Answer - Grignard [GRIN-yerd] reagents are generally made in etherbased solvents due to the instability of the metal-organic species. Identify all of the following\nthree solvents that are considered ethereal: 1) Dioxane;\n2) Tetrahydrofuran [tetrah-high-droh-FYOOR-an]; 3) Dichloromethane.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2\n","answer":"1, 2\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) Biology – Short Answer - A bacterial colony is raised in heavy nitrogen media for several generations, then\ntransferred to a nitrogen-14 medium. Identify all of the following statements that will be true after one generation: 1) Half\nof the bacteria will have denser DNA than the other half; 2) Half of the bacteria will have no heavy nitrogen in their DNA;\n3) Half of the bacteria will have no nitrogen-14 in their DNA.\n","spokenAnswer":"NONE\n","answer":"NONE\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - What is the term for the global variation in sea level\nbrought about by a change in the volume of water occupying the ocean basins?\n","spokenAnswer":"EUSTASY\n","answer":"EUSTASY\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Which of the following statements is correct about the behavior of\nblack bodies?\nW) At high enough temperatures, black bodies will stop emitting in the microwave region\nX) The Stefan-Boltzmann law relates the power radiated by a black body to temperature\nsquared\nY) Approximating a human as a black body shows that most of a person’s energy is radiated\naway as ultraviolet light\nZ) Wien’s law can be used to predict the color of a black body\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) WIEN’S LAW CAN BE USED TO PREDICT THE COLOR OF A BLACK BODY \n","answer":"Z) WIEN’S LAW CAN BE USED TO PREDICT THE COLOR OF A BLACK BODY \n","timer":5},{"question":"15) Energy – Multiple Choice - Which of the following is a type of diode that allows current to flow not only\nin the forward direction normally, but also in the reverse direction at or above the breakdown voltage?\nW) Ideal diode\nX) P-n junction\nY) Zener [zee-ner] diode\nZ) Photodiode\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) ZENER DIODE\n","answer":"Y) ZENER DIODE\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following describes the the ratio between\nthe distance from a point to the center of a black hole and the circumference of a circle around\nthe black hole?\nW) Less than pi\nX) Equal to pi\nY) Greater than pi\nZ) Undefined\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) UNDEFINED\n","answer":"Z) UNDEFINED\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Earth and Space – Short Answer - When a muon [MYOO-on]is created in a laboratory setting, it has a\nlifetime of approximately 2.2 microseconds. When muons are created by cosmic rays, they have speeds of\n99.5% of the speed of light relative to observers on Earth. For an observer on Earth, how long, to two\nsignificant figures and in microseconds, will the lifetime of the cosmic ray muon be?\n","spokenAnswer":"22\n","answer":"22\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - In a recent experiment, you identified an amino acid at the\nactive site of an enzyme. Given your knowledge that basic amino acids are generally found at\nenzyme active sites, which of the following is most likely to be the amino acid that you have\nfound?\nW) Histidine [HIS-ti-deen]\nX) Aspartate\nY) Serine [SER-een]\nZ) Phenylalanine [fen-l-AL-uh-neen]\n","spokenAnswer":"W) HISTIDINE\n","answer":"W) HISTIDINE\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) Physics – Multiple Choice - Which of the following conservation laws is related by Noether\n's theorem to\ntranslational spatial symmetry?\nW) Conservation of mass\nX) Conservation of linear momentum\nY) Conservation of angular momentum\nZ) Conservation of electric charge\n","spokenAnswer":"X) CONSERVATION OF LINEAR MOMENTUM\n","answer":"X) CONSERVATION OF LINEAR MOMENTUM\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Chemistry – Short Answer - What rule, which can be explained by the preferential stability\nof highly substituted carbocations, predicts that the major product in an elimination reaction with\nan unhindered base is the most substituted alkene?\n","spokenAnswer":"ZAITSEV\n'S RULE\n","answer":"ZAITSEV\n'S RULE\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following substances is more soluble in toluene than in\nwater?\nW) Carbon tetrachloride\nX) Sodium chloride\nY) Acetic acid\nZ) Sodium methoxide\n","spokenAnswer":"W) CARBON TETRACHLORIDE\n","answer":"W) CARBON TETRACHLORIDE\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true of\nnuclear chemistry: 1) Helium has a higher binding energy per nucleon than uranium; 2) Alpha\nparticles have a +1 charge; 3) Beta-minus decay usually occurs in nuclei with an excess\nnumber of neutrons.\n","spokenAnswer":"3 ONLY (ACCEPT: BETA-MINUS DECAY USUALLY OCCURS IN NUCLEI WITH AN\n","answer":"3 ONLY (ACCEPT: BETA-MINUS DECAY USUALLY OCCURS IN NUCLEI WITH AN\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following elements has an electron configuration that follows the\nsimple order of orbital filling?\nW) Technetium [tek-NEE-shee-um]\nX) Ruthenium [roo-THEE-nee-um]\nY) Rhodium\nZ) Palladium [pah-LAID-ee-um]\n","spokenAnswer":"W) TECHNETIUM\n","answer":"W) TECHNETIUM\n","timer":20},{"question":"5) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following four phyla [FYE-lah] that exhibit radial\nsymmetry: 1) Porifera [poor-IH-fer-ah]; 2) Cnidaria [nye-DARE-ee-ah]; 3) Mollusca [mull-US-kah];\n4) Echinodermata [eh-kye-noh-der-MAH-tah].\n","spokenAnswer":"2, 4\n","answer":"2, 4\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) Chemistry – Short Answer - What reaction in organic chemistry forms alkenes via a reaction of a\ncarbonyl [carbon-EEL] group with a yellow-colored phosphorous ylide [ILL-id]?\n","spokenAnswer":"WITTIG REACTION\n","answer":"WITTIG REACTION\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - An electron and positron collide and annihilate [uh-NY-uh-layt]\none another. Which of the following is nearest the energy released, in mega electronvolts?\nW) 0.5\nX) 1\nY) 2\nZ) 10\n","spokenAnswer":"X) 1 \n","answer":"X) 1 \n","timer":5},{"question":"21) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - A red breccia contains a high percentage of large\nangular feldspar grains. In what type of depositional environment would you expect it to have\nformed?\nW) Beach\nX) Alluvial fan\nY) Deep ocean trench\nZ) River delta\n","spokenAnswer":"X) ALLUVIAL FAN\n","answer":"X) ALLUVIAL FAN\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) Physics – Multiple Choice - A disc originally at rest moves through 6 radians as it undergoes\na constant angular acceleration about its central axis. If the time taken to accelerate is 2 seconds,\nwhat is the magnitude of the acceleration in radians per square second?\nW) 3\nX) 6\nY) 9\nZ) 12\n","spokenAnswer":"W) 3\n","answer":"W) 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) Energy – Short Answer - What country is the source of the largest percentage of petroleum imported to the US?\n","spokenAnswer":"CANADA\n","answer":"CANADA\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) PHYSICS Short Answer - An ideal gas is enclosed within a container with a movable piston\nas the lid. The gas is initially at a pressure of 3 atmospheres and occupies a volume of 2 liters.\nThe piston is lowered so that the gas now occupies 1.5 liters at a pressure of P. If the process\nwas carried out slowly, maintaining constant temperature in contact with a suitable reservoir,\nwhat is P in atmospheres?\n","spokenAnswer":"4\n","answer":"4\n","timer":5},{"question":"4) Math – Short Answer - What is the limit as x approaches 0 of the fraction with numerator\nx – 1 + e to the power 3x and denominator sine x?\n","spokenAnswer":"4\n","answer":"4\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true regarding nutrition:\n1) Leptin suppresses appetite; 2) Ghrelin [greh-lihn] suppresses appetite; 3) A rise in blood sugar stimulates\nthe beta cells of the pancreas.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 3\n","answer":"1 AND 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) MATH Short Answer - Providing your answer as an improper fraction in lowest terms, solve\nthe following equation for x over the real numbers: [9 to the power of 2x equals\n27 to the power of the quantity 3x minus 4].\n","spokenAnswer":"12/5\n","answer":"12/5\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) Physics – Short Answer - List two of the experiments performed at the Large Hadron\nCollider at CERN in Europe.\n","spokenAnswer":"Any two of the following: ATLAS, CMS, LHCb, ALICE, ToTEM, LHCf, MoEDAL\n","answer":"Any two of the following: ATLAS, CMS, LHCb, ALICE, ToTEM, LHCf, MoEDAL\n","timer":5},{"question":"18) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - X-rays with a wavelength of 150 picometers are scattered at\nan angle of 15 degrees by a crystal. Assuming that this was first-degree scattering, which of the\nfollowing is closest to the spacing in this crystal, in picometers?\nW) 145\nX) 155\nY) 290\nZ) 589\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) 290\n","answer":"Y) 290\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following types of DNA damage or distortion would\nbe most likely to lead to an insertion or deletion during replication, resulting in a frameshift\nmutation?\nW) Depurination\nX) Alkylation [al-kuh-LAY-shuhn]\nY) Tautomerization [taw-TOM-uh-ri-ZAY-shuhn]\nZ) Intercalation\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) INTERCALATION\n","answer":"Z) INTERCALATION\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What is the dominant gas of the Martian atmosphere?\n","spokenAnswer":"CARBON DIOXIDE\n","answer":"CARBON DIOXIDE\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) MATH Short Answer - Evaluate the following expression: ∑ ݊ ଵସ ଶ\n\nu0be1ୀଵ [the sum from n equals one\nto fourteen of n squared]\n","spokenAnswer":"1015\n","answer":"1015\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Which principle of quantum mechanics determines the transition\nprobability for a molecule, based on the overlap of its vibrational states?\n","spokenAnswer":"FRANK-CONDON \n","answer":"FRANK-CONDON \n","timer":20},{"question":"3) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Which approximation is used in quantum mechanics to separate\nthe electronic and vibrational wave functions into isolated components?\n","spokenAnswer":"BORN-OPPENHEIMER\n","answer":"BORN-OPPENHEIMER\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) Energy – Short Answer - Researchers at Pacific Northwest National Lab are studying\nO-linked glycosylation [glye-kaw-sil-AY-shun] of the tau protein. This post-translational process\nplays a role in the pathogenesis [path-oh-JEN-eh-sis] of what human disease?\n","spokenAnswer":"ALZHEIMER’S DISEASE\n","answer":"ALZHEIMER’S DISEASE\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) Biology – Short Answer - In E. coli, a certain gene undergoes a mutation such that the resulting protein is much\nlarger in size and now non-functional. What type of mutation likely occurred?\n","spokenAnswer":"INSERTION\n","answer":"INSERTION\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) Energy – Short Answer - Researchers at Princeton Plasma Physics Lab are studying the\nAlpha Centauri star system. This system contains how many stars?\n","spokenAnswer":"THREE\n","answer":"THREE\n","timer":20},{"question":"23) MATH Short Answer - There is a well-shuffled deck of 52 cards containing 13 cards each of\nspades, clubs, diamonds, and hearts. You draw 2 cards without replacement. What is the\nprobability that both cards are diamonds?\n","spokenAnswer":"1/17\n","answer":"1/17\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true regarding a\nchemical reaction where delta G is negative and the change in entropy is negative: 1) Requires energy; 2) Is\nexergonic; 3) Increases the disorder in a system.\n","spokenAnswer":"2 \n","answer":"2 \n","timer":20},{"question":"10) Math – Short Answer - What is the approximation for the sine of 2 that results from using the first\nthree nonzero terms of the Taylor series for sine x centered at 0?\n","spokenAnswer":"14/15\n","answer":"14/15\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Comet McNaught visited in 2007 but is now on a path to leave the solar system\nforever. Which of the following best describes its orbit?\nW) Circular\nX) Elliptical\nY) Parabolic\nZ) Hyperbolic\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) HYPERBOLIC\n","answer":"Z) HYPERBOLIC\n","timer":20},{"question":"15) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - If a single nucleotide is inserted into the middle of the protein\ncoding sequence of a gene, which of the following is the likely outcome?\nW) A frameshift mutation that leads to multiple missense and/or nonsense mutations\nX) A single codon will have a missense mutation\nY) One codon will have a missense or nonsense mutation, and the another nucleotide [NOOklee-uh-tyd] will be deleted\nZ) A frameshift mutation that is silent\n","spokenAnswer":"W) A FRAMESHIFT MUTATION THAT LEADS TO MULTIPLE MISSENSE AND/OR\n","answer":"W) A FRAMESHIFT MUTATION THAT LEADS TO MULTIPLE MISSENSE AND/OR\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Given the balanced equation: 2C4H10(g) + 13O2(g) → 8CO2(g) +\n10H2O(g), what is the percent yield of water if 15 moles of water is obtained when 4 moles of\nbutane is burned in excess oxygen?\n","spokenAnswer":"75%\n","answer":"75%\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following mechanisms transfers angular\nmomentum in accretion disks?\nW) Viscosity\nX) Gravity\nY) Advection\nZ) Coriolis forces\n","spokenAnswer":"W) VISCOSITY\n","answer":"W) VISCOSITY\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) Math – Short Answer - What is the following cross product of vectors: 5i – 3j + k cross 4j?\n","spokenAnswer":"–4i + 20k\n","answer":"–4i + 20k\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) Biology – Short Answer - What is the name of the jelly-like fluid that fills the human eye?\n","spokenAnswer":"VITREOUS HUMOR (ACCEPT: VITREOUS BODY)\n","answer":"VITREOUS HUMOR (ACCEPT: VITREOUS BODY)\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - The rostral bone evolved to allow for the powerful\nbeak-like bite characteristic of what dinosaur group?\nW) Therapods\nX) Ceratopsians [ser-uh-TOP-see-uhns]\nY) Sauropods [SAWR-uh-pods]\nZ) Hadrosaurs [HAD-ruh-sawrs]\n","spokenAnswer":"X) CERATOPSIANS\n","answer":"X) CERATOPSIANS\n","timer":20},{"question":"14) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - All except which of the following can act as direct substrates for\nthe production of acetyl CoA?\nW) Lactate\nX) Amino acids\nY) Fatty acids\nZ) Ketone bodies\n","spokenAnswer":"W) LACTATE\n","answer":"W) LACTATE\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) Earth and Space – Short Answer - In 1967, Jocelyn Bell detected a regularly pulsing radio signal, which she called\nLGM. What type of celestial object produced this signal?\n","spokenAnswer":"PULSAR (DO NOT ACCEPT: NEUTRON STAR)\n","answer":"PULSAR (DO NOT ACCEPT: NEUTRON STAR)\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What is the name for a location on Earth that does not have tides?\n","spokenAnswer":"AMPHIDROMIC POINT (ACCEPT: TIDAL NODES)\n","answer":"AMPHIDROMIC POINT (ACCEPT: TIDAL NODES)\n","timer":5},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following ocean currents does NOT flow from\nhigher latitudes toward the equator?\nW) The California Current\nX) The Peru Current\nY) The Brazil Current\nZ) The Benguela [ben-GWAY-la] Current\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) THE BRAZIL CURRENT\n","answer":"Y) THE BRAZIL CURRENT\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) Physics – Multiple Choice - Which of the following types of magnetometers needs to be\ncooled to very low temperatures due to reliance on the Josephson effect?\nW) Overhauser\nX) SERF [surf]\nY) SQUID [squid]\nZ) Fluxgate\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) SQUID\n","answer":"Y) SQUID\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Energy – Multiple Choice - DOE scientists are using the Advanced Light Source to study atmospheric\nreentry heat shields, including PICA [PEE-kah], the type currently used by NASA and SpaceX. Which of\nthe following best describes PICA?\nW) A silicone-based heating pad\nX) A highly-thermally-conductive epoxy\nY) A carbon fiber that slowly ablates\nZ) Titanium shingles with heat sinks\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) A CARBON FIBER THAT SLOWLY ABLATES\n","answer":"Y) A CARBON FIBER THAT SLOWLY ABLATES\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three fatty acids that are unsaturated: 1) C13H27COOH;\n2) C17H35COOH; 3) C16H29COOH.\n","spokenAnswer":"JUST 3\n","answer":"JUST 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Bungarotoxin [bung-garoh-TOK-sins] is a fast-acting lethal toxin\nthat is the primary component of venom from the South Asian snake called a krait. It blocks\nnerve transmission at cholinergic [koh-luh-NUR-jik] synapses by competing with acetylcholine\n[uh-seet-l-KOH-leen] to bind irreversibly at the acetylcholine receptor. Which of the following\nwould be LEAST LIKELY to also impact nerve transmission at the cholinergic synapses?\nW) A drug floods the synapse with a molecule that resembles acetylcholine and is able to bind\nat the acetylcholine receptor, but cannot be recognized by acetylcholinesterase [uh-seet-lKOH-leen-STUH-rays]\nX) A chemical covalently binds to the acetylcholine receptor and is not easily inactivated\nY) A chemical covalently bonds acetylcholinesterase at the enzyme active site\nZ) A drug increases the level of acetylcholinesterase present at the synapse\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) A DRUG INCREASES THE LEVEL OF ACETYLCHOLINESTERASE PRESENT\n","answer":"Z) A DRUG INCREASES THE LEVEL OF ACETYLCHOLINESTERASE PRESENT\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - Which of the following molecules contains only one nonbonding pair of valence electrons?\nW) HCN\nX) NH4\n+\nY) C2H4\nZ) N2\n","spokenAnswer":"W) HCN\n","answer":"W) HCN\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) Chemistry – Short Answer - Consider a reaction that is nonspontaneous at 300 kelvins, but\nbecomes spontaneous when the temperature is raised to 400 kelvins. Identify all of the following\nthree values that are positive for this reaction at 300 kelvins: 1) Delta-H; 2) Delta-S; 3) Delta-G.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2, AND 3 (ACCEPT: ALL)\n","answer":"1, 2, AND 3 (ACCEPT: ALL)\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) Biology – Multiple Choice - Which of the following nucleobases is NOT a pyrimidine\n[pur-RIM-ih-deen]?\nW) Guanine [GWAH-neen]\nX) Cytosine [SYE-toh-seen]\nY) Thymine [THIGH-meen]\nZ) Uracil [YUR-ah-sil]\n","spokenAnswer":"W) GUANINE\n","answer":"W) GUANINE\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - In the unified model of active galactic nuclei (AGN),\nwhat is the most important variable that determines what class of AGN is observed?\nW) Orientation angle\nX) Metallicity\nY) Supermassive black hole age\nZ) Galaxy type\n","spokenAnswer":"W) ORIENTATION ANGLE\n","answer":"W) ORIENTATION ANGLE\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Physics – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three quantities that are dimensionless:\n1) Tensile [TEN-sile] stress; 2) Tensile strain; 3) Young’s Modulus.\n","spokenAnswer":"2\n","answer":"2\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) MATH Short Answer - What is the name of the point at which the three angle bisectors of a\ntriangle intersect?\n","spokenAnswer":"INCENTER\n","answer":"INCENTER\n","timer":20},{"question":"10) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three reactions that would result in a precipitate.\n1) Addition of barium nitrate and sodium sulfate; 2) Addition of aluminum nitrate and zinc sulfate; 3)\nAddition of sodium hydroxide and ammonium sulfate.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 ONLY\n","answer":"1 ONLY\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) Biology – Short Answer - Methylation [meth-il-AY-shun] of cytosine [sigh-toh-seen] was once thought to play an\nimportant role in repressing gene regulation. Deamination [dee-am-ih-NAY-shun] of\n5-methylcytosine [five methil-SYE-toh-seen] results in the production of what other nucleobase?\n","spokenAnswer":"THYMINE\n","answer":"THYMINE\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) Chemistry – Short Answer - What functional group is formed when hot sulfuric acid is used\nto dehydrate an alcohol?\n","spokenAnswer":"ALKENE [al-KEEN]\n","answer":"ALKENE [al-KEEN]\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Biology – Short Answer - What is the term for mobile elements of DNA that can cut and paste themselves into new\nlocations?\n","spokenAnswer":"TRANSPOSONS\n","answer":"TRANSPOSONS\n","timer":20},{"question":"24) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Consider the track of the 2005 Hurricane Katrina.\nAlabama’s Dauphin Island suffered more extreme damage than other islands exposed to the\nstorm. Based on the nature of hurricanes, what quadrant of the storm pounded Dauphin Island?\nW) Northeast\nX) Northwest\nY) Southwest\nZ) Southeast\n","spokenAnswer":"W) NORTHEAST\n","answer":"W) NORTHEAST\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Energy – Multiple Choice - Which heavy metal element, used in photovoltaic thin films, has raised\nconcerns about ecological bioaccumulation due to its high toxicity?\nW) Vanadium\nX) Tungsten\nY) Cadmium\nZ) Cobalt\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) CADMIUM\n","answer":"Y) CADMIUM\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - In ecology, there are two rules that identify relationships\nbetween the animal’s habitat and its shape and structure. Bergmann’s rule predicts that body\nsize decreases in proximity to the equator, while Allen’s rule predicts that appendages increase\nin size in proximity to the equator. Which of the following represents the basis for these\npredictions?\nW) Small animals have a higher survival rate at the equator because of the dense foliage\nX) There is less competition for food in the Arctic, so animals can grow larger\nY) Animals with a low surface area to volume ratio can conserve heat more easily\nZ) The foundation for understanding both rules is based on Gloger’s rule\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) ANIMALS WITH A LOW SURFACE AREA TO VOLUME RATIO CAN\n","answer":"Y) ANIMALS WITH A LOW SURFACE AREA TO VOLUME RATIO CAN\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) Energy – Short Answer - Recent work at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory has\nlinked what metal to the health of the brain, showing that improper oxidation is not only linked\nto Alzheimer\n's disease, but also that it modulates spontaneous activity in developing circuits?\n","spokenAnswer":"COPPER\n","answer":"COPPER\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) BIOLOGY Short Answer - What is the term for an inanimate object that is capable of\ntransmitting infectious disease from one individual to another?\n","spokenAnswer":"FOMITE\n","answer":"FOMITE\n","timer":5},{"question":"12) Math – Short Answer - What is the distance between the two points with polar coordinates\nof r = 4 and theta = 60 degrees, and r = 6 and theta = 0 degrees?\n","spokenAnswer":"2√7\n","answer":"2√7\n","timer":20},{"question":"11) Physics – Short Answer - How much work, in joules [jools], is done on a particle of charge 2 coulombs as it\naccelerates over a distance of 1 meter in an electric field of strength 9 volts per meter?\n","spokenAnswer":"18\n","answer":"18\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) BIOLOGY Short Answer - What cellular process, associated with regeneration, can\nspontaneously occur in lower animals but not in humans?\n","spokenAnswer":"DEDIFFERENTIATION\n","answer":"DEDIFFERENTIATION\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - “Soda-lime” glass accounts for 90% of the glass produced and\ncan be made by mixing a modifier, or flux, with sand. Which of the following is an example of a\nsoda-lime glass modifier?\nW) SiO2\nX) Ca(OH)2\nY) Na2O\nZ) MgO\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) Na2O\n","answer":"Y) Na2O\n","timer":5},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following statements is NOT true\nregarding the planet Mercury?\nW) Mercury is more massive than Ganymede\nX) Mercury has a magnetic field generated by a liquid iron core\nY) Mercury is synchronously tidally locked with the Sun\nZ) Craters on Mercury\n's north pole are known to contain water ice\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) MERCURY IS SYNCHRONOUSLY TIDALLY LOCKED WITH THE SUN\n","answer":"Y) MERCURY IS SYNCHRONOUSLY TIDALLY LOCKED WITH THE SUN\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following stars has a positive apparent\nmagnitude?\nW) Polaris\nX) Sirius\nY) Canopus\nZ) The Sun\n","spokenAnswer":"W) POLARIS\n","answer":"W) POLARIS\n","timer":5},{"question":"19) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - A lady in a spacecraft travelling away from the Earth at 4/5 the\nspeed of light gives birth to a child at 1:00 p.m., which, according to the spacecraft’s clock, is\nonly 3 hours after the spacecraft departed from the Earth. Assuming constant acceleration\nduring those 3 hours, what is the child\n's birth time according to a stationary clock on the Earth?\nW) 2:00 p.m.\nX) 4:00 p.m.\nY) 6:00 p.m.\nZ) 7:30 p.m.\n","spokenAnswer":"W) 2:00 p.m.\n","answer":"W) 2:00 p.m.\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following statements best describes how\nchlorine adds to an alkene [al-KEEN]?\nW) Both chlorine atoms add to the same carbon atom\nX) Chlorine atoms add with syn-stereoselectivity [sin-stereo-see-lek-TIV-ih-tee] to adjacent\ncarbon atoms\nY) Chlorine atoms add with anti-stereoselectivity to adjacent carbon atoms\nZ) Only one chlorine atom adds to the carbon atoms\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) CHLORINE ATOMS ADD WITH ANTI-STEREOSELECTIVITY TO\n","answer":"Y) CHLORINE ATOMS ADD WITH ANTI-STEREOSELECTIVITY TO\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) Biology – Short Answer - What organelle is defective in inclusion-cell disease, also known\nas I-cell disease?\n","spokenAnswer":"LYSOSOME\n","answer":"LYSOSOME\n","timer":20},{"question":"11) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - What chemical, produced by planktonic algae, is the\nmajor source of cloud-condensation nuclei over the open oceans?\nW) Nitric acid\nX) Dimethyl sulphide [dy-METH-uhl SUHL-fyd]\nY) Hydrochloric acid\nZ) Sodium carbonate peroxyhydrate [puh-rok-see-HY-drayt]\n","spokenAnswer":"X) DIMETHYL SULPHIDE\n","answer":"X) DIMETHYL SULPHIDE\n","timer":5},{"question":"12) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Which of the following ways will allow you to increase the\ncapacitance of a parallel-plate capacitor?\nW) Decreasing the plate separation\nX) Increasing the plate separation\nY) Decreasing the surface area of each plate\nZ) Increasing the charge on the plates\n","spokenAnswer":"W) DECREASING THE PLATE SEPARATION\n","answer":"W) DECREASING THE PLATE SEPARATION\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) Physics – Short Answer - Identify all of the following 4 heat engine cycles which use internal\ncombustion: 1) Diesel; 2) Carnot; 3) Otto; 4) Rankine.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 3\n","answer":"1 AND 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) Math – Short Answer - Find the value of a for which the following vectors are\nperpendicular: 9i – 3j and ai + 36j.\n","spokenAnswer":"12\n","answer":"12\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following is NOT in the order Artiodactyla [art-eeoh-DAK-tuh-luh]?\nW) Chevrotain\nX) Warthog\nY) Giraffe\nZ) Hyrax\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) HYRAX\n","answer":"Z) HYRAX\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) MATH Short Answer - Given the equation: x + 1/x = 3 [x plus 1 over x equals 3], what is\nthe value of x4 + 1/x4 [x to the fourth plus 1 over x to the fourth]?\n","spokenAnswer":"47\n","answer":"47\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) MATH Short Answer - You are given that xy = 6 and x2\ny + xy2\n + x + y = 63 [x times y equals six\nand x squared times y plus x times y squared plus x plus y equals sixty-three]. Calculate:\nx2\n + y2 [x squared plus y squared].\n","spokenAnswer":"69\n","answer":"69\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Energy – Short Answer - Scientists at Lawrence Berkeley National Lab are part of the\nCUORE collaboration that is attempting to observe what ghostly leptons?\n","spokenAnswer":"NEUTRINOS\n","answer":"NEUTRINOS\n","timer":20},{"question":"15) Energy – Short Answer - Scientists at Brookhaven National Lab use the Relativistic Heavy\nIon Collider to study a state of matter thought to have also existed in the early universe. This\nmatter is composed of quarks and what other strongly-interacting fundamental particles?\n","spokenAnswer":"GLUONS\n","answer":"GLUONS\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following classes of stars does NOT\nhave radiative zones?\nW) A\nX) G\nY) M\nZ) O\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) M\n","answer":"Y) M\n","timer":20},{"question":"20) Math – Short Answer - How many terms does the binomial expansion of open parenthesis 8x3 + 5y2\nclose parenthesis to 18th power contain?\n","spokenAnswer":"19\n","answer":"19\n","timer":5},{"question":"24) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - How is the ratio of oxygen-18 to oxygen-16 useful in\nserving as a proxy for paleoclimatic [pay-lee-oh-kly-MAH-tik] temperatures in ice-core\nsamples?\nW) Oxygen-16 is preferentially stored in ice and only released during warmer periods\nX) Oxygen-16 changes into oxygen-18 at higher temperatures\nY) Oxygen-18 is released from water molecules at higher temperatures\nZ) Water with oxygen-18 freezes at lower temperatures than water with oxygen-16\n","spokenAnswer":"W) OXYGEN-16 IS PREFERENTIALLY STORED IN ICE AND ONLY RELEASED\n","answer":"W) OXYGEN-16 IS PREFERENTIALLY STORED IN ICE AND ONLY RELEASED\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Physics – Short Answer - Indicate what Gaussian surface would most simplify the calculation of the flux\nof the electric field for each of the following three configurations: 1) Point charge; 2) Infinitely long line of\nuniform charge; 3) Infinitely large sheet of uniform charge\n","spokenAnswer":"1 - SPHERE, 2 - CYLINDER, 3 - CYLINDER or PILLBOX\n","answer":"1 - SPHERE, 2 - CYLINDER, 3 - CYLINDER or PILLBOX\n","timer":5},{"question":"19) Physics – Short Answer - Consider a configuration of two identical point charges that are\n1 meter apart, and which has a potential energy of 1 joule. To two significant figures and in\njoules, what is the potential energy of a configuration where four such point charges are placed\nin a square with side length 1 meter?\n","spokenAnswer":"5.4\n","answer":"5.4\n","timer":20},{"question":"10) Math – Multiple Choice - The graph of a continuous function f contains the points (3, –6)\nand (8, –4). The intermediate value theorem guarantees an x-value such that f of x equals which\nof the following?\nW) –5\nX) –2\nY) 2\nZ) 5\n","spokenAnswer":"W) –5\n","answer":"W) –5\n","timer":5},{"question":"19) Physics – Short Answer - What quantity, inversely related to compressibility, measures a material’s\nability to resist pressures coming from all sides, such as when underwater?\n","spokenAnswer":"BULK MODULUS\n","answer":"BULK MODULUS\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three conditions that negatively\nimpact short term memory: 1) Post traumatic stress disorder; 2) Aphasia [ah-FAY-sjah]; 3)\nAlzheimer\n's.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2, 3 (ACCEPT: ALL OF THEM)\n","answer":"1, 2, 3 (ACCEPT: ALL OF THEM)\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) ENERGY Multiple Choice - If you heat a container of gas at a higher temperature than its\nsurroundings to twice its prior absolute temperature without changing the temperature of its\nenvironment, you have done which of the following?\nW) Increased the system\n's enthalpy and decreased its entropy\nX) Increased the system\n's enthalpy and entropy\nY) Decreased the system\n's enthalpy and entropy\nZ) Decreased the system\n's enthalpy and increased its entropy\n","spokenAnswer":"X) INCREASED THE SYSTEM\n'S ENTHALPY AND ENTROPY\n","answer":"X) INCREASED THE SYSTEM\n'S ENTHALPY AND ENTROPY\n","timer":20},{"question":"10) Math – Short Answer - What is the absolute value of the complex conjugate of –6 + i?\n","spokenAnswer":"√37\n","answer":"√37\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following four compounds that are polar:\n1) XeF4; 2) SF4; 3) BrF5; 4) PF5.\n","spokenAnswer":"2 AND 3\n","answer":"2 AND 3\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following correctly describes why antifungal\nmedications are often harder to design than antibacterials?\nW) Antifungals must target peptidoglycan [pep-ti-doh-GLY-kan]\nX) Both fungi and humans are eukaryotes [yoo-KAR-ee-ohts]\nY) Bacteria and humans have similar cellular structures\nZ) Most antifungals target chitin building enzymes\n","spokenAnswer":"X) BOTH FUNGI AND HUMANS ARE EUKARYOTES\n","answer":"X) BOTH FUNGI AND HUMANS ARE EUKARYOTES\n","timer":5},{"question":"1) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - By name or number, identify where fine-grained\nterrigenous deposits are most likely to form: 1) abyssal plains, 2) atolls, 3) deep-sea fans, 4)\ncontinental margins, or 5) elevated oceanic ridges.\n","spokenAnswer":"ABYSSAL PLAINS (ACCEPT: 1)\n","answer":"ABYSSAL PLAINS (ACCEPT: 1)\n","timer":20},{"question":"3) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - If magnetic monopoles exist, which of the following Maxwell’s\nequations would be changed?\nW) Gauss’s law for magnetism only\nX) Gauss’s law for magnetism and Ampere’s law\nY) Gauss’s law for magnetism and Faraday’s law\nZ) Gauss’s law for magnetism, Ampere’s law, and Faraday’s law\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) GAUSS’S LAW FOR MAGNETISM AND FARADAY’S LAW\n","answer":"Y) GAUSS’S LAW FOR MAGNETISM AND FARADAY’S LAW\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) Physics – Short Answer - A certain steel guitar has strings of length 1 meter and cross\nsectional area 2 times 10 –6 square meter. If the Young’s modulus of steel is 2 times 1011 newtons\nper square meter, then in newtons, what is the tension in the string when it is stretched 0.02\nmeter for tuning?\n","spokenAnswer":"8000\n","answer":"8000\n","timer":20},{"question":"24) ENERGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following is NOT an advantage of radio-frequency\naccelerators?\nW) The technology is well established\nX) Emittance dominates transverse beam dynamics during acceleration and storage, rather than\nspace charge\nY) Obtaining the required ion energy is straightforward due to the high acceleration gradients in\nradio-frequency structures\nZ) Storage rings are not needed since beams can be compressed in length as they are\naccelerated\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) STORAGE RINGS ARE NOT NEEDED SINCE BEAMS CAN BE COMPRESSED\n","answer":"Z) STORAGE RINGS ARE NOT NEEDED SINCE BEAMS CAN BE COMPRESSED\n","timer":5},{"question":"19) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - The wavelength shift of light from a quasar gives the recessional\nspeed v ≈ 2.18 × 108 meters per second. If the Hubble constant is 21.8 millimeters per second\nper light year, what is the approximate distance of the quasar in light years?\nW) 108\nX) 109\nY) 1010\nZ) 1011\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) 1010\n","answer":"Y) 1010\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) Math – Short Answer - Consider rolling a six-sided die three times. What is the probability that the three\nresults are strictly increasing?\n","spokenAnswer":"5/54\n","answer":"5/54\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) ENERGY Short Answer - Identify all of the following three changes that would increase the\nhalf-life of a first order reaction: 1) increasing the starting concentration; 2) decreasing the\nstarting concentration; 3) increasing the rate constant.\n","spokenAnswer":"3 (ACCEPT: INCREASING THE RATE CONSTANT)\n","answer":"3 (ACCEPT: INCREASING THE RATE CONSTANT)\n","timer":20},{"question":"15) Energy – Multiple Choice - Scientists at Oak Ridge National Lab have designed a fuel rod\ncladding alloy made of iron, chromium, and aluminum to replace current zirconium alloys.\nWhich of the following must be a property of this cladding?\nW) Converts fast neutrons into thermal neutrons\nX) Converts thermal neutrons into fast neutrons\nY) Has a high neutron cross-section\nZ) Has a low neutron cross-section\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) HAS A LOW NEUTRON CROSS-SECTION\n","answer":"Z) HAS A LOW NEUTRON CROSS-SECTION\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) ENERGY Multiple Choice - Plasmas are considered strongly coupled when the ratio of the\naverage distance between the particles to the distance of closest approach is which of the\nfollowing?\nW) Small\nX) Large\nY) Roughly equal to one\nZ) Roughly equal to zero\n","spokenAnswer":"W) SMALL\n","answer":"W) SMALL\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) Physics – Multiple Choice - In a rectifier, which of the following pairs of current types\ndescribes the input and output of the device, respectively?\nW) DC-AC\nX) DC-DC\nY) AC-DC\nZ) AC-AC\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) AC-DC\n","answer":"Y) AC-DC\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) BIOLOGY Short Answer - Hemosiderin [hee-moh-SID-er-in] is a protein used to store what\nchemical that can be toxic when free in the cell?\n","spokenAnswer":"IRON (ACCEPT: IRON-2, FERRITIN)\n","answer":"IRON (ACCEPT: IRON-2, FERRITIN)\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following is true of sandstone formed\nfrom a long-term paleodesert?\nW) It would exhibit clearly graded bedding\nX) It would have preserved ripples but not dunes\nY) It would appear black due to the dark iron-rich minerals present\nZ) It would contain well rounded grains and have high quartz content\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) IT WOULD CONTAIN WELL ROUNDED GRAINS AND HAVE HIGH QUARTZ\n","answer":"Z) IT WOULD CONTAIN WELL ROUNDED GRAINS AND HAVE HIGH QUARTZ\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) Energy – Short Answer - In a junction transistor used as a switch, which terminal controls the current through the\nother two terminals?\n","spokenAnswer":"BASE\n","answer":"BASE\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Which of the following particles are classified as baryons?\nW) Weak boson\nX) Graviton\nY) Neutrino\nZ) Neutron\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) NEUTRON\n","answer":"Z) NEUTRON\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three chemical reactions that are\nlikely to be spontaneous at room temperature: 1) Solid sodium combines with chlorine gas to\nform solid sodium chloride; 2) Gaseous nitrogen combines with gaseous hydrogen to form\ngaseous ammonia;\n3) Solid potassium iodide dissolves into potassium and iodide ions.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 3\n","answer":"1, 3\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) Math – Short Answer - A set of test scores is normally distributed with mean 62 and standard\ndeviation 8. What score corresponds to a Z-score of –1.25?\n","spokenAnswer":"52\n","answer":"52\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three characteristics that\ndescribe regular satellites: 1) Prograde orbit; 2) Low orbital inclination; 3) Low orbital\neccentricity.\n","spokenAnswer":"ALL OF THEM\n","answer":"ALL OF THEM\n","timer":20},{"question":"10) Energy – Multiple Choice - Oil shale is a type of organic-rich sedimentary rock that can be used to produce shale oil,\nalso known as tight oil, which is a substitute for conventional crude oil. Which of the following varieties of oil shale is\nNOT classified as a marine shale?\nW) Kukersite\nX) Torbanite\nY) Tasminite\nZ) Marinite\n","spokenAnswer":"X) TORBANITE\n","answer":"X) TORBANITE\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) Biology – Multiple Choice - Which of the following hormones most directly affects the\nmetabolic rate of the body?\nW) Thyroid-stimulating hormone\nX) Thyrotropin-releasing hormone\nY) Triiodothyronine [try-eye-oh-doh-THIGH-roh-neen]\nZ) Testosterone\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) TRIIODOTHYRONINE\n","answer":"Y) TRIIODOTHYRONINE\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Math – Short Answer - A prism with 24 edges has how many faces?\n","spokenAnswer":"10\n","answer":"10\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) ENERGY Short Answer - The presence of what class of compounds in nuclear reactors slows\ndown the neutrons in the core, preventing the development of a potential nuclear bomb?\n","spokenAnswer":"MODERATORS (DO NOT ACCEPT: CONTROL RODS)\n","answer":"MODERATORS (DO NOT ACCEPT: CONTROL RODS)\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) Math – Short Answer - The point (3, –7) is reflected through the y-axis, with the result then\ntranslated 2 units left. What are the coordinates of the final image?\n","spokenAnswer":"(–5, –7)\n","answer":"(–5, –7)\n","timer":5},{"question":"4) Physics – Short Answer - Consider a circuit in which two light bulbs with equal resistance\nvalues are connected in parallel. If one of the light bulbs burns out, by what factor is the\nbrightness of the other bulb multiplied?\n","spokenAnswer":"ONE\n","answer":"ONE\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - In active meiosis, new genetic combinations can arise in two\ndifferent ways. Which of the following is the first stage in which there could be genetic\nrecombination?\nW) Anaphase I\nX) Anaphase II\nY) Prophase I\nZ) Prophase II\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) PROPHASE I\n","answer":"Y) PROPHASE I\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Categorize each of the following four examples of isomerism as\neither structural isomerism or stereoisomerism [ster-ee-oh-EYE-suh-mer]: 1) geometrical; 2)\nionization; 3) polymerization [puh-lim-er-uh-ZAY-shuhn]; 4) optical.\n","spokenAnswer":"STRUCTURAL ISOMERISM: 2, 3 (IONIZATION, POLYMERIZATION);\n","answer":"STRUCTURAL ISOMERISM: 2, 3 (IONIZATION, POLYMERIZATION);\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - What kind of surveying attempts to determine what the\nsea floor looks like, focusing on water depth and nature of sea floor material, and supporting\nactivities such as nautical charting, dredging, coastal engineering, and offshore resource\ndevelopment?\n","spokenAnswer":"HYDROGRAPHIC\n","answer":"HYDROGRAPHIC\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true regarding a neuron\nat rest: 1) Voltage-gated sodium channels are mostly open; 2) Voltage-gated potassium channels are mostly\nopen; 3) The sodium-potassium pump is hydrolyzing [HIGH-droh-lyzing] ATP.\n","spokenAnswer":"3\n","answer":"3\n","timer":20},{"question":"3) Earth and Space – Short Answer - 21-centimeter radiation is observed throughout much of space because it is\ngenerated from the neutral form of what element?\n","spokenAnswer":"HYDROGEN\n","answer":"HYDROGEN\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - The observation that the mean luminosity of more\ndistant stars tends to be higher than the mean luminosity of nearby stars in a flux-limited sample\nis an example of which of the following kinds of bias?\nW) Eddington\nX) Selection\nY) Confirmation\nZ) Hindsight\n","spokenAnswer":"X) SELECTION\n","answer":"X) SELECTION\n","timer":20},{"question":"3) Physics – Multiple Choice - Taking the acceleration due to gravity to be 10 meters per\nsecond squared, how much power, in watts, is required to lift a 2 kilogram mass at a constant\nspeed of 2 meters per second?\nW) 2\nX) 4\nY) 40\nZ) 80\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) 40\n","answer":"Y) 40\n","timer":5},{"question":"6) Physics – Short Answer - What is the name of the low-temperature state characterized by zero resistance transport of\nelectron pairs?\n","spokenAnswer":"SUPERCONDUCTIVITY\n","answer":"SUPERCONDUCTIVITY\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true of nitrogenous\n[nye-TRAW-jen-us] waste excretion: 1) Ammonia excretion results in more water loss than an equivalent\namount of urea excretion; 2) Urea is more energetically expensive to excrete than an equivalent amount of\nuric [YUR-ik] acid; 3) Humans produce a small amount of uric acid.\n","spokenAnswer":"ALL\n","answer":"ALL\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) ENERGY Short Answer - What extremely powerful biological oxidizing agent is used in\nphotosynthesis to oxidize water and is named for its absorption maximum in the red part of the\nvisible spectrum?\n","spokenAnswer":"P680 (ACCEPT: PIGMENT 680) \n","answer":"P680 (ACCEPT: PIGMENT 680) \n","timer":20},{"question":"8) PHYSICS Short Answer - By number, give all of the following three statements that are true of\nCarnot engines: 1) Carnot’s theorem limits the efficiency of engines to less than that of a Carnot\nengine; 2) The Carnot cycle consists of only reversible steps; 3) The concept of entropy arose\nfrom the limits stated by the Carnot cycle.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2, 3 (ACCEPT: ALL OF THEM)\n","answer":"1, 2, 3 (ACCEPT: ALL OF THEM)\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following was the LEAST common use\nof a typical astrolabe?\nW) Finding the time of day\nX) Finding the time of a celestial event\nY) Reference for celestial positions\nZ) Maritime navigational instrument\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) MARITIME NAVIGATIONAL INSTRUMENT \n","answer":"Z) MARITIME NAVIGATIONAL INSTRUMENT \n","timer":20},{"question":"5) Biology – Multiple Choice - Which of the following amino acids is typically phosphorylated\n[faws-FOR-il-ated] by protein kinase A?\nW) Tyrosine\nX) Serine\nY) Tryptophan\nZ) Isoleucine\n","spokenAnswer":"X) SERINE\n","answer":"X) SERINE\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What cinder cone appeared in 1943 in a Mexican corn field and is one\nof the most well characterized cinder cone volcanoes?\n","spokenAnswer":"PARICUTIN\n","answer":"PARICUTIN\n","timer":20},{"question":"20) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What stellar spectral class tends to have the strongest\nsingly-ionized helium absorption lines?\n","spokenAnswer":"O [Oh]\n","answer":"O [Oh]\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) Math – Short Answer - The graph of the polar equation r = 6 cosine theta is a circle. What are its\nradius and cartesian-coordinate center, respectively?\n","spokenAnswer":"RADIUS 3, CENTER (3, 0) (ACCEPT: x = 3 AND y = 0 for center)\n","answer":"RADIUS 3, CENTER (3, 0) (ACCEPT: x = 3 AND y = 0 for center)\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three types of trees that are\nconsidered to be gymnosperms: 1) Cycads [SIGH-cads]; 2) Conifers; 3) Ginkgos.\n","spokenAnswer":"ALL OF THEM\n","answer":"ALL OF THEM\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Scientists can study solar fusion via observations of certain near-massless particles\nthat travel through the Sun. What are these particles?\n","spokenAnswer":"NEUTRINOS\n","answer":"NEUTRINOS\n","timer":20},{"question":"20) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Identify all of the following four elements that would burn red\nwhen subjected to a flame test: 1) lithium; 2) selenium; 3) barium; 4) calcium.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 4 (ACCEPT: LITHIUM AND CALCIUM)\n","answer":"1 AND 4 (ACCEPT: LITHIUM AND CALCIUM)\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - The secondary rainbow in a double rainbow requires\nwhich of the following optical processes?\nW) One refraction and two internal reflections\nX) One internal reflection and two refractions\nY) Two internal reflections and two refractions\nZ) Two refractions, one reflection, and surface diffraction\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) TWO INTERNAL REFLECTIONS AND TWO REFRACTIONS\n","answer":"Y) TWO INTERNAL REFLECTIONS AND TWO REFRACTIONS\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following is NOT true of the platypus?\nW) They are one of the few venomous mammals\nX) They lack teats\nY) Their eggs are holoblastic\nZ) They have ten sex chromosomes\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) THEIR EGGS ARE HOLOBLASTIC\n","answer":"Y) THEIR EGGS ARE HOLOBLASTIC\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) Math – Short Answer - What is the integral with respect to x from 9 to 64 of the derivative of the\nsquare root of x?\n","spokenAnswer":"5\n","answer":"5\n","timer":20},{"question":"5) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three bile components that are secreted by\nhepatocytes: 1) Bile salts; 2) Bilirubin; 3) Bicarbonate.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 2\n","answer":"1 AND 2\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) Biology – Short Answer - In humans, circadian [sir-KAY-dee-an] rhythms are controlled by a specific\ngroup of neurons in the hypothalamus [high-poh-THAL-ah-mus] called what?\n","spokenAnswer":"SCN (ACCEPT: SUPRACHIASMATIC NUCLEUS)\n","answer":"SCN (ACCEPT: SUPRACHIASMATIC NUCLEUS)\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three molecules that have the chemical\nformula C4H8O: 1) Acetone; 2) Butanone; 3) Butyraldehyde.\n","spokenAnswer":"2 AND 3\n","answer":"2 AND 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) Math – Short Answer - The graph of f of x = the fraction with numerator x2 – 2x – 24 and\ndenominator x2 – 16 has a removable discontinuity at x = a for some real number a. What is the\nlimit as x approaches a of f of x?\n","spokenAnswer":"5/4 (ACCEPT: 1¼, 1.25)\n","answer":"5/4 (ACCEPT: 1¼, 1.25)\n","timer":20},{"question":"14) Physics – Short Answer - When looking at it through a plane mirror, a flagpole appears to be 10\ncentimeters tall. Given that the eye-to-mirror distance is 0.4 meters and the total eye-to-mirror-to-pole\ndistance is 30 meters, what is the actual height, in meters, of the flagpole?\n","spokenAnswer":"7.5 (ACCEPT: 15/2, 7½ )\n","answer":"7.5 (ACCEPT: 15/2, 7½ )\n","timer":5},{"question":"4) ENERGY Short Answer - What specific compound has emerged as a potential redox active\nmaterial choice for two-step thermochemical cycling due to its rapid fuel production kinetics and\nhigh selectivity?\n","spokenAnswer":"CERIUM (IV) OXIDE (ACCEPT: CeO2, CERIA, CERIC OXIDE)\n","answer":"CERIUM (IV) OXIDE (ACCEPT: CeO2, CERIA, CERIC OXIDE)\n","timer":20},{"question":"10) MATH Short Answer - Evaluate ∫ 𝑥2\n(𝑥3+3)2 𝑑𝑑 ∞\n1 [the integral from 1 to infinity of the fraction\nwith numerator x squared and denominator open parenthesis x cubed plus 3 close\nparenthesis squared dx].\n","spokenAnswer":"1/12\n","answer":"1/12\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true of\neukaryotic mRNA processing: 1) The 5-prime end is capped with a modified cytosine [sigh-tohseen] residue; 2) The 5-prime end is capped in the nucleus; 3) The 3-prime end is adenylated in\nthe cytosol.\n","spokenAnswer":"2\n","answer":"2\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) ENERGY Short Answer - Microwave ovens work by creating radiation energy that is\nabsorbed by the water, fats, and sugars in food, which in turn is converted to atomic motion and\nheat. Providing your answer in scientific notation with one significant figure, if the wavelength of\nmicrowave radiation is 10 centimeters, what is the frequency in hertz?\n","spokenAnswer":"3 x 109\n","answer":"3 x 109\n","timer":5},{"question":"12) ENERGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following processes is used to produce additional\nATP for the light-independent reactions of photosynthesis?\nW) Cyclic electron flow\nX) Lactic acid fermentation\nY) Glycolysis [gly-KOL-uh-sis]\nZ) Beta oxidation\n","spokenAnswer":"W) CYCLIC ELECTRON FLOW\n","answer":"W) CYCLIC ELECTRON FLOW\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following is NOT one of the seven crystal lattice systems?\nW) Orthorhombic\nX) Monoclinic\nY) Octagonal\nZ) Cubic\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) OCTAGONAL\n","answer":"Y) OCTAGONAL\n","timer":5},{"question":"2) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following molecular geometries can exhibit meridional isomerism?\nW) Linear\nX) Square planar\nY) Tetrahedral\nZ) Octahedral\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) OCTAHEDRAL\n","answer":"Z) OCTAHEDRAL\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three choices that are true of fairy rings: 1) The\noldest portion of the fungus is at the center of the fairy ring; 2) The center of the fairy ring is absorbing the\nmost nutrients per unit time relative to the rest of the ring; 3) The outer edge of the fairy ring is where one\ncould find basidiocarps.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 3\n","answer":"1 AND 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"6) MATH Multiple Choice - Which of the following best represents the conversion of the\nrectangular coordinates (3, 4) into polar coordinates?\nW) (5, 37o)\nX) (37o, 5)\nY) (5, 53o)\nZ) (53o, 5)\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) (5, 53o)\n","answer":"Y) (5, 53o)\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following is the rate at which\natmospheric gases and particles are moved across a surface?\nW) Vertical dispersion\nX) Turbulence\nY) Flux\nZ) Stratospheric transport\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) FLUX\n","answer":"Y) FLUX\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - Ozonolysis [oh-zuh-NOL-uh-sis] cleaves which of the\nfollowing?\nW) Carbon-carbon double bonds in alkenes [AL-keens]\nX) Carbon-carbon bonds in alkanes\nY) Oxygen-oxygen bonds\nZ) Bonds between carbon and hydrogen\n","spokenAnswer":"W) CARBON-CARBON DOUBLE BONDS IN ALKENES\n","answer":"W) CARBON-CARBON DOUBLE BONDS IN ALKENES\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three quantities that have\nincreased globally due to human activities: 1) Flux of sediment into the oceans from streams; 2)\nArea of rainforest in the tropics; 3) Total volume of groundwater in aquifers.\n","spokenAnswer":"1\n","answer":"1\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Math – Short Answer - In a circle with radius 4, what is the area of a circular segment\ndefined by an arc of 45°?\n","spokenAnswer":"2pi - 4√2 \n","answer":"2pi - 4√2 \n","timer":20},{"question":"6) Math – Short Answer - What is the sum of the first 6 terms in the geometric sequence with\nfirst term 3 and second term 12?\n","spokenAnswer":"4095\n","answer":"4095\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) MATH Multiple Choice - Which of the following is a first order non-linear ordinary differential\nequation?\nW) y\n' + y = 0 [y prime plus y equals zero]\nX) y\n'’ - 2y\n2 - 2 = 0 [y double prime minus 2y squared minus 2 equals zero]\nY) y\n' - xy = 0 [y prime minus xy equals zero]\nZ) y\n' - 2y2 - 2 = 0 [y prime minus 2y squared minus two equals zero]\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) y\n' - 2y2 - 2 = 0\n","answer":"Z) y\n' - 2y2 - 2 = 0\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) Biology – Multiple Choice - Which of the following medications would likely be most\neffective in treating a human patient with influenza?\nW) Penicillin\nX) Ampicillin\nY) Zanamivir [zeh-NAM-ih-veer]\nZ) Chloroquine [KLOR-oh-queen]\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) ZANAMIVIR\n","answer":"Y) ZANAMIVIR\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) ENERGY Short Answer - Water is the product of four-electron transfer in a polymer\nelectrolyte membrane fuel cell; what is the product of two-electron transfer?\n","spokenAnswer":"HYDROGEN PEROXIDE (ACCEPT: H2O2)\n","answer":"HYDROGEN PEROXIDE (ACCEPT: H2O2)\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - A galaxy is receding from an observer such that the\nhydrogen alpha line appears to be at 657 nanometers instead of 656.3 nanometers. Which of the\nfollowing best describes the changes in the beta and gamma lines for this galaxy?\nW) They will both be shifted longer by 0.7 nanometers\nX) They will both be shifted by slightly less than 0.7 nanometers\nY) They will both be shifted by slightly more than 0.7 nanometers\nZ) They will both be shifted shorter by 0.7 nanometers\n","spokenAnswer":"X) THEY WILL BOTH BE SHIFTED BY SLIGHTLY LESS THAN 0.7\n","answer":"X) THEY WILL BOTH BE SHIFTED BY SLIGHTLY LESS THAN 0.7\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Lapilli [lah-PILL-eye] and cinders are subtypes of what\nmaterials that are ejected from volcanoes?\n","spokenAnswer":"PYROCLAST (ACCEPT TEPHRA, PYROCLASTIC DEBRIS)\n","answer":"PYROCLAST (ACCEPT TEPHRA, PYROCLASTIC DEBRIS)\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three latitudes that trade winds can be\nfound in: 1) Between 60 and 30 degrees south; 2) Between 30 degrees south and the equator; 3) Between\nthe equator and 30 degrees north.\n","spokenAnswer":"2 AND 3\n","answer":"2 AND 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) Energy – Multiple Choice - Scientists at Los Alamos National Lab are measuring the\npositron flux in Earth’s upper atmosphere. Which of the following is NOT TRUE concerning\npositrons?\nW) They decay into muons\nX) They have a positive charge\nY) They are first-generation leptons\nZ) They can interact with electrons to generate two gamma rays\n","spokenAnswer":"W) THEY DECAY INTO MUONS\n","answer":"W) THEY DECAY INTO MUONS\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - A transgressive stratigraphic sequence can be related to\nwhich of the following events?\nW) Sea-level rise\nX) Orogeny [or-AW-jeh-nee]\nY) Oxbow lake formation\nZ) Significant rainfall events\n","spokenAnswer":"W) SEA-LEVEL RISE\n","answer":"W) SEA-LEVEL RISE\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - Which of the following bonds is the longest in length?\nW) Fluorine-fluorine\nX) Chlorine-chlorine\nY) Bromine-bromine\nZ) Iodine-iodine\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) IODINE-IODINE\n","answer":"Z) IODINE-IODINE\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - The amino acid sequence of a protein represents the translation\nof which of the following?\nW) The template DNA strand\nX) The nontemplate DNA strand\nY) The tRNA nucleotide sequence [NOO-klee-uh-tyd]\nZ) The reverse-complement of the mRNA strand\n","spokenAnswer":"X) THE NONTEMPLATE DNA STRAND\n","answer":"X) THE NONTEMPLATE DNA STRAND\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) MATH Short Answer - For a line passing through the point (1, 0, -1) and parallel to the vector\n(2, 1, 4), give the parametric equations for x, y, and z.\n","spokenAnswer":"x = 1 + 2t, y = t, z = -1 + 4t\n","answer":"x = 1 + 2t, y = t, z = -1 + 4t\n","timer":20},{"question":"11) Energy – Multiple Choice - Lithium cobalt oxide is most commonly used for what\ncomponent of a lithium-ion battery?\nW) Electrolyte\nX) Cathode\nY) Enclosure\nZ) Anode\n","spokenAnswer":"X) CATHODE\n","answer":"X) CATHODE\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Math – Short Answer - In the integers mod 12, what is 7 times 11?\n","spokenAnswer":"5\n","answer":"5\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) Chemistry – Short Answer - The rate of a reaction between reagent A and reagent B is first\norder in B. By what factor is the rate of reaction multiplied if the concentration of reagent B is\ndoubled?\n","spokenAnswer":"2\n","answer":"2\n","timer":5},{"question":"2) Chemistry – Short Answer - Marie places 4.4 grams of dry ice in a vacuum-sealed 5-liter bag\nat standard temperature. After the dry ice reaches standard temperature, then, to the nearest tenth\nof a liter, how much volume will it fill?\n","spokenAnswer":"2.2\n","answer":"2.2\n","timer":20},{"question":"6) Energy – Short Answer - What element is the least dense metal, has the most negative electrochemical\npotential, and has the greatest energy density, making it an excellent battery half-cell?\n","spokenAnswer":"LITHIUM\n","answer":"LITHIUM\n","timer":5},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What was the most abundant atmospheric gas during the\nProterozoic [proh-tair-oh-ZOH-ik] Eon?\n","spokenAnswer":"NITROGEN (ACCEPT: DINITROGEN, N2)\n","answer":"NITROGEN (ACCEPT: DINITROGEN, N2)\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) Math – Short Answer - A set of test scores is normally distributed with mean 72 and standard deviation 6. What\nscore corresponds to a Z-score of –1.5?\n","spokenAnswer":"63\n","answer":"63\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) Math – Short Answer - What is the smallest positive zero of the function with equation\ny = 2 sine open parenthesis 3x + 3π over 5 close parenthesis?\n","spokenAnswer":"2π/15 (ACCEPT: (2/15)π)\n","answer":"2π/15 (ACCEPT: (2/15)π)\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) Biology – Short Answer - Starting with the fixation of atmospheric nitrogen and ending with\nthe assimilation of nitrogen compounds by plants, order the following three ions of the nitrogen\ncycle chronologically: 1) Ammonium; 2) Nitrate; 3) Nitrite.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 3, 2\n","answer":"1, 3, 2\n","timer":5},{"question":"18) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following marine snails produces a deadly toxin?\nW) Blood ark\nX) Amethyst olive\nY) Eastern melampus\nZ) Geographic cone\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) GEOGRAPHIC CONE\n","answer":"Z) GEOGRAPHIC CONE\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Copper (II) hydroxide is insoluble in water. However, upon the\naddition of excess ammonia, it dissolves and changes to a deep blue color. Which of the following\nstatements best explains this observation?\nW) The rise in pH solubilized the copper hydroxide\nX) The drop in pH solubilized the copper hydroxide\nY) The copper reacted with ammonia, forming a soluble species\nZ) The ammonia neutralized the hydroxide, releasing soluble copper (II)\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) THE COPPER REACTED WITH AMMONIA, FORMING A SOLUBLE SPECIES\n","answer":"Y) THE COPPER REACTED WITH AMMONIA, FORMING A SOLUBLE SPECIES\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following statements is NOT true about the G\nprotein hormone receptor system?\nW) It is an example of membrane-based signal transduction\nX) It results in an amplification of the original signal\nY) The hormone is a ligand for the G protein\nZ) The G protein must be able to move along the membrane\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) THE HORMONE IS A LIGAND FOR THE G PROTEIN\n","answer":"Y) THE HORMONE IS A LIGAND FOR THE G PROTEIN\n","timer":20},{"question":"5) BIOLOGY Short Answer - An unknown substance is tested by 2 reagents. The Lugol’s test\nyields a black color while the Benedict’s test yields a light blue color. Amylase is added and then\nthe substance is retested. The second Lugol’s test is negative, while the second Benedict’s test\nyields a red color. What substances were present before and after, respectively, the amylase\nwas added?\n","spokenAnswer":"POLYSACCHARIDE (ACCEPT: STARCH, DO NOT ACCEPT: GLYCOGEN) AND\n","answer":"POLYSACCHARIDE (ACCEPT: STARCH, DO NOT ACCEPT: GLYCOGEN) AND\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true regarding plant hormones:\n1) Auxin plays an important role in gravitropism; 2) Abscisic [ab-SIH-zik] acid inhibits primary and secondary growth; 3)\nCytokinin [sigh-toh-KYE-nin] increases rate of leaf senescence [sen-EH-sense].\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 2\n","answer":"1 AND 2\n","timer":20},{"question":"25) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Providing your answer to one significant figure, determine the\npH of a 5.0 molar solution of acetic acid, given that acetic acid’s Ka is 2 x 10-5\n.\n","spokenAnswer":"2\n","answer":"2\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) Biology – Short Answer - What protein structure forms between homologous chromosomes during\nmeiosis and is thought to mediate chromosomal pairing?\n","spokenAnswer":"SYNAPTONEMAL COMPLEX\n","answer":"SYNAPTONEMAL COMPLEX\n","timer":20},{"question":"11) MATH Short Answer - Under what arithmetic operation is the set of even integers NOT\nclosed?\n","spokenAnswer":"DIVISION\n","answer":"DIVISION\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) PHYSICS Short Answer - An electron microscope enables observation of detail on a virus\ndown to 6 nanometers. Given h as 6.6 x 10−\n34 joule seconds and the mass of the electron as 9.1\nx 10−\n31 kilograms, providing your answer in scientific notation with two significant digits, how fast,\nin meters per second, must an electron in the microscope be moving to observe detail of this\nsize?\n","spokenAnswer":"1.2 × 105\n","answer":"1.2 × 105\n","timer":20},{"question":"24) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following is the double-degenerate model\nfor Type Ia supernovae [soo-per-NOH-vee]?\nW) The cores of a binary system undergo common envelope evolution collapse and explode\nafter iron fusion\nX) A red giant overflows its Roche [ROHSH] lobe and dumps matter onto a white dwarf until the\nwhite dwarf exceeds the Chandrasekhar [chun-druh-SAY-ker] mass\nY) Two white dwarfs collide to create a new object, which exceeds the Chandrasekhar mass\nZ) A main sequence star overflows its Roche lobe and dumps matter onto a white dwarf until the\nwhite dwarf exceeds the Chandrasekhar mass\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) TWO WHITE DWARFS COLLIDE TO CREATE A NEW OBJECT, WHICH\n","answer":"Y) TWO WHITE DWARFS COLLIDE TO CREATE A NEW OBJECT, WHICH\n","timer":5},{"question":"18) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What object, as a result of tidal heating, is the most\nvolcanically active body in the solar system?\n","spokenAnswer":"IO\n","answer":"IO\n","timer":20},{"question":"10) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Some disease-causing microbes attack the body by turning on\nor off specific signal transduction pathways. In the disease cholera, for example, a toxin from\nthe bacterium Vibrio cholera enters intestinal cells and chemically modifies G proteins. Once\nmodified, the G proteins can no longer cleave GTP into GDP. Which of the following would you\nexpect to see within the intestinal cells of a person with cholera?\nW) The G proteins remain activated and continually activate adenylyl cylase\nX) The G proteins cannot become activated and cannot activate adenylyl cylase\nY) The G protein subunits do not separate from each other\nZ) The receptor in the membrane is continually activated\n","spokenAnswer":"W) THE G PROTEINS REMAIN ACTIVATED AND CONTINUALLY ACTIVATE\n","answer":"W) THE G PROTEINS REMAIN ACTIVATED AND CONTINUALLY ACTIVATE\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - In two-photon fluorescence spectroscopy, it is common to use a\nmolecule that has a very strong two-photon absorption cross-section. What are the names of\nthe highly fluorescent and commonly used molecules that are generally abbreviated CV and\nGFP?\n","spokenAnswer":"CRYSTAL VIOLET AND GREEN FLUORESCENT PROTEIN\n","answer":"CRYSTAL VIOLET AND GREEN FLUORESCENT PROTEIN\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following methods could be used to separate a pair of\nenantiomers?\nW) Gravity filtration\nX) Normal silica gel column chromatography\nY) Mass spectrometry\nZ) Kinetic resolution\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) KINETIC RESOLUTION\n","answer":"Z) KINETIC RESOLUTION\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are TRUE\nconcerning crystal field theory: 1) Carbon monoxide is a strong-field ligand; 2) Tetrahedral\nsplitting is larger than octahedral splitting; 3) Square planar compounds can be chiral.\n","spokenAnswer":"1\n","answer":"1\n","timer":20},{"question":"23) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - What was the principle reason that the Kapteyn\nmodel and the Shapley model of the size of the Galaxy were incorrect?\nW) They only examined the distribution of stars and failed to examine the distribution of globular\nclusters\nX) They used data that was not sensitive enough to detect the faintest stars in the Galaxy\nY) They failed to account for extinction due to dust\nZ) They only examined the distribution of globular clusters and failed to examine the distribution\nof stars\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) THEY FAILED TO ACCOUNT FOR EXTINCTION DUE TO DUST\n","answer":"Y) THEY FAILED TO ACCOUNT FOR EXTINCTION DUE TO DUST\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - A student wishes to convert an aldehyde to a secondary alcohol. Which\nof the following reagents would be most useful?\nW) Alkyl [AL-keel] Grignard [GRIN-yerd] reagent\nX) Lithium aluminum hydride\nY) Sodium borohydride\nZ) Sodium hydride\n","spokenAnswer":"W) ALKYL GRIGNARD REAGENT\n","answer":"W) ALKYL GRIGNARD REAGENT\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) Physics – Short Answer - Consider a 200-newton-meter torque [tork] that acts on a solid disk\nof radius one meter and mass 100 kilograms. What is the angular velocity of the disk after 5\nseconds, in radians per second?\n","spokenAnswer":"20\n","answer":"20\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Adding ethyl-magnesium bromide to which of the following\nwould produce a tertiary [TUR-shee-ary] alcohol?\nW) A ketone\nX) An aldehyde\nY) An alkene [al-KEEN]\nZ) An ether\n","spokenAnswer":"W) A KETONE\n","answer":"W) A KETONE\n","timer":20},{"question":"25) MATH Multiple Choice - You are conducting an experiment. In a large elementary school,\nyou select two age-matched groups of students. Group 1 follows a normal schedule. Group 2\nspends 30 minutes a day in art class in addition to their other classes. You want to test whether\nlearning art makes a student less likely to get in trouble. You consider a student in trouble if he\nor she was sent to the principal’s office at any time during the year. The data you collect would\nBEST be analyzed by which of the following?\nW) Two populations, difference in means, paired data\nX) Two populations, difference in means, unpaired data\nY) Two populations, difference in proportions\nZ) Two populations, contingency table\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) TWO POPULATIONS, DIFFERENCE IN PROPORTIONS\n","answer":"Y) TWO POPULATIONS, DIFFERENCE IN PROPORTIONS\n","timer":5},{"question":"6) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true of\nSDS-PAGE: 1) It requires addition of antioxidant to the inner gel chamber; 2) It requires protein\ndenaturation using urea; 3) It relies on SDS binding proportional to protein mass.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 3\n","answer":"1, 3\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three ligands that are considered\nbidentate: 1) Oxalate; 2) Ethylene-diamine; 3) Cyanide.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2\n","answer":"1, 2\n","timer":5},{"question":"2) Math – Short Answer - What is the sum of the squares of the first 19 positive integers?\n","spokenAnswer":"2470\n","answer":"2470\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) Physics – Short Answer - Similar to his famous gold foil experiment, Rutherford bombarded\nnitrogen-14 atoms with alpha particles, and observed that each event released a proton. Into what\nisotope was the nitrogen converted?\n","spokenAnswer":"OXYGEN-17\n","answer":"OXYGEN-17\n","timer":5},{"question":"2) Physics – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three quantities that are quantized: 1) Atoms of H2O\nin a beaker; 2) Frequencies of light emitted by an excited atom; 3) Charge stored on a parallel-plate\ncapacitor.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2, AND 3\n","answer":"1, 2, AND 3\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Earth and Space – Short Answer - The addition of what metal to the Earth\n's oceans has been proposed as a potential\nway to decrease atmospheric carbon dioxide through the stimulation of photosynthetic bacteria?\n","spokenAnswer":"IRON\n","answer":"IRON\n","timer":5},{"question":"1) Math – Multiple Choice - If x + y = 1 and x minus y equals the product of the square root of 2 and the sine\nof theta, what is x times y?\nW) Cosine of 2 theta\nX) Sine of 2 theta\nY) One-fourth the cosine of 2 theta\nZ) One-fourth the sine of 2 theta\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) ONE-FOURTH THE COSINE OF 2 THETA\n","answer":"Y) ONE-FOURTH THE COSINE OF 2 THETA\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) MATH Short Answer - Two planes are orthogonal to each other. How many lines exist that are\na given fixed distance d from both of these planes?\n","spokenAnswer":"FOUR\n","answer":"FOUR\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Math – Short Answer - Simplify i raised to the 22nd power.\n","spokenAnswer":"–1\n","answer":"–1\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) Math – Short Answer - What are the x-coordinates of the intersections of the graphs of the equations\ny = 9x2 + 3 and y = –27x + 3?\n","spokenAnswer":"0 AND –3\n","answer":"0 AND –3\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) Biology – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three disorders that are usually inherited dominantly:\n1) Huntington’s disease; 2) Albinism [AL-beh-nih-zim]; 3) Polydactyly [polly-DAK-til-ee].\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 3\n","answer":"1 AND 3\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) ENERGY Multiple Choice - Nanticoke Generating Station, located in southern Ontario,\nCanada, is one of the world\n's largest coal-burning power plants. However, the Canadian\nMinistry of Energy announced in 2010 that Nanticoke would convert some of their generators to\nuse which of the following types of fuel instead of coal?\nW) Natural gas\nX) Uranium-238\nY) Petroleum\nZ) Ethanol\n","spokenAnswer":"W) NATURAL GAS\n","answer":"W) NATURAL GAS\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What was the first black hole discovered?\n","spokenAnswer":"CYGNUS X-1\n","answer":"CYGNUS X-1\n","timer":20},{"question":"3) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following systems of climate\nclassification is the best-known and most used?\nW) Trewartha\nX) Klaus\nY) Köppen\nZ) Strahler\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) KÖPPEN\n","answer":"Y) KÖPPEN\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Kearns-Sayre Syndrome is caused by a mutation on a gene in\nthe mitochondrial [my-tuh-KON-dree-uhl] DNA. Both males and females can have the disease,\nbut the disease can only be transmitted to a child by the mother, never the father. Why is this\nso?\nW) The gene is on the X chromosome, and females are XX\nX) The sperm that fertilizes the egg contributes only its chromosomes and none of its\nmitochondria\nY) The mutant protein is only active in the egg, not the sperm\nZ) The disease is sex-limited\n","spokenAnswer":"X) THE SPERM THAT FERTILIZES THE EGG ONLY CONTRIBUTES ITS\n","answer":"X) THE SPERM THAT FERTILIZES THE EGG ONLY CONTRIBUTES ITS\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) Biology – Short Answer - What microsatellite genetic markers do forensic scientists\ntypically use for crime scene DNA analysis?\n","spokenAnswer":"STRs (ACCEPT: SHORT TANDEM REPEATS)\n","answer":"STRs (ACCEPT: SHORT TANDEM REPEATS)\n","timer":5},{"question":"2) Math – Short Answer - What is the cube of the complex number 3 + 5i?\n","spokenAnswer":"–198 + 10i\n","answer":"–198 + 10i\n","timer":20},{"question":"11) Physics – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three types of imaging that depend\non ionizing radiation: 1) Magnetic resonance imaging; 2) Computerized\ntomography [tom-AW-grafee]; 3) Positron emission tomography.\n","spokenAnswer":"2, 3\n","answer":"2, 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"6) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Amniotes became very well adapted to life on land. Which of the\nfollowing is not an adaptation of amniotes to a terrestrial existence?\nW) Eggs resistant to desiccation\nX) Buccal pumping\nY) Water-conserving kidneys\nZ) Thoracic breathing\n\n","spokenAnswer":"X) BUCCAL PUMPING\n","answer":"X) BUCCAL PUMPING\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) Biology – Short Answer - A scientist crosses a pea plant that is true breeding for the dominant traits of round and\nyellow seeds with a plant that is true breeding for wrinkled, green seeds. What fraction of the offspring will have round,\ngreen seeds?\n","spokenAnswer":"0\n","answer":"0\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following is the best approximation of how much time a supergiant\nstar can survive by way of silicon fusion?\nW) 1 day\nX) 1 year\nY) 1 thousand years\nY) 1 million years\n","spokenAnswer":"W) 1 DAY\n","answer":"W) 1 DAY\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) Biology – Short Answer - Bacteria use what cellular structure for motility?\n","spokenAnswer":"FLAGELLUM\n","answer":"FLAGELLUM\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) BIOLOGY Short Answer - What is the name of the symbiont that can have crustose, foliose, or\nfruiticose forms?\n","spokenAnswer":"LICHEN\n","answer":"LICHEN\n","timer":20},{"question":"5) Energy – Multiple Choice - The energy price spikes in the 1970s and in 2008 suggested which of the following about\nU.S. energy usage?\nW) Usage rises in response to rising prices\nX) Usage stays the same when prices rise\nY) Usage drops in response to rising prices\nZ) There was no consistent trend about U.S. energy usage\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) USAGE DROPS IN RESPONSE TO RISING PRICES\n","answer":"Y) USAGE DROPS IN RESPONSE TO RISING PRICES\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) Energy – Short Answer - Researchers at Oak Ridge National Lab have been examining how\nglaucoma drugs interact with a human enzyme that converts carbon dioxide and water to\nbicarbonate. What is the common name of this enzyme?\n","spokenAnswer":"CARBONIC ANHYDRASE (ACCEPT: HUMAN CARBONIC ANHYDRASE)\n","answer":"CARBONIC ANHYDRASE (ACCEPT: HUMAN CARBONIC ANHYDRASE)\n","timer":20},{"question":"14) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - How many lone pairs of electrons are on the phosphorus atom\nin PF3?\n","spokenAnswer":"1\n","answer":"1\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) Math – Short Answer - The Seven Bridges of Konigsberg was a historically notable problem in graph\ntheory and topology that was resolved by what mathematician?\n","spokenAnswer":"LEONHARD EULER\n","answer":"LEONHARD EULER\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) Physics – Multiple Choice - An electron is moving along the x-axis in the positive direction,\nwithin a uniform magnetic field that is oriented toward the positive z-axis. In which of the\nfollowing directions does the Lorentz [lohr-ENZ] force act?\nW) Positive y-axis\nX) Negative y-axis\nY) Positive z-axis\nZ) Negative z-axis\n","spokenAnswer":"W) POSITIVE y-AXIS\n","answer":"W) POSITIVE y-AXIS\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) Physics – Short Answer - How much energy, in joules, is in a single kilo-watt hour?\n","spokenAnswer":"3.6 MILLION (ACCEPT: 3 MILLION 6 HUNDRED THOUSAND)\n","answer":"3.6 MILLION (ACCEPT: 3 MILLION 6 HUNDRED THOUSAND)\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Given that the balanced chemical equation for the reaction of\noxygen and ethane is: 2C2H6(g) + 7O2(g) → 4CO2(g) + 6H2O(g), if 16 grams of O2 react with excess\nC2H6, to the nearest gram, how many grams of CO2 will be formed?\n","spokenAnswer":"13\n","answer":"13\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Earth and Space – Short Answer - The C-N-O process in massive stars is responsible for\nfusing what element into heavier nuclides?\n","spokenAnswer":"HYDROGEN\n","answer":"HYDROGEN\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - What is the name for the gravitational equilibrium [eekwuh-LIB-ree-uhm] points in the orbital plane of two bodies?\n","spokenAnswer":"LAGRANGIAN POINT (ACCEPT: LAGRANGE POINT)\n","answer":"LAGRANGIAN POINT (ACCEPT: LAGRANGE POINT)\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Energy – Short Answer - Scientists at Lawrence Berkeley National Lab are developing\nthermoelectric materials that can convert thermal energy to electrical energy via what effect?\n","spokenAnswer":"SEEBECK EFFECT (ACCEPT: PELTIER-SEEBECK EFFECT, DO NOT\n","answer":"SEEBECK EFFECT (ACCEPT: PELTIER-SEEBECK EFFECT, DO NOT\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - A soil sample is extracted from a soil monolith in a temperate\nforest environment. The sample contains a relatively high concentration of sand and silt as well as leached\nminerals. What soil horizon does the sample represent?\nW) A\nX) B\nY) C\nZ) E\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) E\n","answer":"Z) E\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What stadial, also referred to as the Big Freeze, was a period of cold\nclimatic conditions approximately 12,000 years ago?\n","spokenAnswer":"YOUNGER DRYAS\n","answer":"YOUNGER DRYAS\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Deuterochloroform [DOO-ter-uh-KLAWR-uh-fawrm] is often\nused as the internal standard in carbon-13 nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy. At what\nchemical shift value in parts per million is the resonance centered?\n","spokenAnswer":"77.0 (ACCEPT: 77)\n","answer":"77.0 (ACCEPT: 77)\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) Earth and Space – Short Answer - An asteroid revolves around the Sun every 64 Earth-years.\nTo the nearest whole astronomical unit, what is the semimajor axis of the asteroid?\n","spokenAnswer":"16\n","answer":"16\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) Biology – Multiple Choice - Which of the following correctly describes the difference\nbetween peptoids, or poly-N-substituted glycines, and proteins?\nW) Peptoids have less constrained secondary structure than proteins\nX) Peptoids cannot possess tertiary structure, while proteins can\nY) Peptoids form more stable alpha helices than proteins\nZ) Peptoids form more stable beta sheets than proteins\n","spokenAnswer":"W) PEPTOIDS HAVE LESS CONSTRAINED SECONDARY STRUCTURE\n","answer":"W) PEPTOIDS HAVE LESS CONSTRAINED SECONDARY STRUCTURE\n","timer":5},{"question":"21) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Muscle fibers can be classified as slow, intermediate, or fast.\nWhich of the following is NOT true regarding fast muscle fibers?\nW) They are found in higher relative abundance in world class sprinters versus world class\nmarathoners\nX) They fatigue most rapidly\nY) They have the highest mitochondrial density\nZ) The primary pathway for ATP production is fermentation\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) THEY HAVE THE HIGHEST MITOCHONDRIAL DENSITY\n","answer":"Y) THEY HAVE THE HIGHEST MITOCHONDRIAL DENSITY\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following insect orders is characterized by the beak\nor stylet arising from the posterior part of the head and extending along the insect’s sternum?\nW) Hymenoptera [hy-muh-NOP-ter-uh]\nX) Homoptera [hoh-MOHP-tuh-ruh]\nY) Coleoptera [koh-lee-OP-ter-uh]\nZ) Hemiptera [hi-MIP-ter-uh]\n","spokenAnswer":"X) HOMOPTERA\n","answer":"X) HOMOPTERA\n","timer":5},{"question":"21) Physics – Short Answer - What quark was most recently discovered?\n","spokenAnswer":"TOP QUARK\n","answer":"TOP QUARK\n","timer":20},{"question":"24) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - When the lunar surface is bombarded with solar\nwind, which of the following resources may be exploited from the Moon\n's surface?\nW) Helium for nuclear fusion\nX) Iron for steel\nY) Sulfur for acids\nZ) Silicon for computer technologies\n","spokenAnswer":"W) HELIUM FOR NUCLEAR FUSION\n","answer":"W) HELIUM FOR NUCLEAR FUSION\n","timer":5},{"question":"18) PHYSICS Short Answer - A 2.0 kilogram possum hangs from a tree limb 5 meters above the\nground. Assuming that the gravitational potential energy is zero at y = 0 and that g is 9.8 meters\nper second squared, what is the gravitational potential energy, to the nearest joule, of the\npossum-Earth system if we take the reference point y = 0 to be 1.0 meters above the limb?\n","spokenAnswer":"-20\n","answer":"-20\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) ENERGY Short Answer - A nuclear power plant is situated on the bank of a river. The power\nplant produces 200 megawatts of power and releases 1.5 × 1013 joules of heat per day into the\nriver through the cooling system. If the flow rate of the river is 5.0 × 104 kilograms per second\nand the specific heat of water is 4.2 × 103 joules per kilogram degree Celsius, what is the\nmaximum temperature increase of the river water due to the cooling system, in degrees Celsius\nto the nearest integer?\n","spokenAnswer":"1\n","answer":"1\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following statements is NOT correct regarding\nshort day plants?\nW) Flowering occurs when night length is less than critical length\nX) Continuity of darkness is crucial; flowering will not occur if darkness is interrupted by a\nmomentary light flash\nY) Short day plants are synonymous with long night plants\nZ) Photoperiod can be detected via phytochromes\n","spokenAnswer":"W) FLOWERING OCCURS WHEN NIGHT LENGTH IS LESS THAN CRITICAL\n","answer":"W) FLOWERING OCCURS WHEN NIGHT LENGTH IS LESS THAN CRITICAL\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Heat, Q, is added to a monatomic ideal gas under conditions of constant\nvolume, resulting in a temperature change, delta T. How much heat will be required to produce the same\ntemperature change, if it is added under conditions of constant pressure?\nW) 3/5 Q\nX) Q\nY) 5/3 Q\nZ) 2 Q\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) 5/3 Q\n","answer":"Y) 5/3 Q\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - How much volcanic material, in cubic kilometers, does a\nvolcano have to eject to be considered an 8 on the Volcanic Explosivity Index, or VEI?\n","spokenAnswer":"1000\n","answer":"1000\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) MATH Short Answer - A national achievement test is administered. The test has a mean\nscore of 100 and a standard deviation of 15. If Vince’s z-score is 1.20, what is his score on the\ntest?\n","spokenAnswer":"118\n","answer":"118\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) Math – Short Answer - If air leaves a spherical balloon at a rate of 1 cubic centimeter per\nsecond, at what rate in centimeters per second is the radius changing when the radius is 1/2\ncentimeter?\n","spokenAnswer":"–1/pi (ACCEPT: DECREASING BY 1/pi; DO NOT ACCEPT: 1/pi)\n","answer":"–1/pi (ACCEPT: DECREASING BY 1/pi; DO NOT ACCEPT: 1/pi)\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) ENERGY Multiple Choice - Which of the following cooking pot materials is most useful for an\ninduction cooktop?\nW) Copper\nX) Cast iron\nY) Aluminum\nZ) Glass\n","spokenAnswer":"X) CAST IRON\n","answer":"X) CAST IRON\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) MATH Short Answer - An object is moving along a line in such a way that its position s at time\nt seconds is given by s = 4t\n3\n - 12t\n2\n + 24t [s equals four t cubed minus twelve t squared plus\ntwenty-four t]. Determine the minimum velocity of the object, in units per second.\n","spokenAnswer":"12\n","answer":"12\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three numbers of π [pie]-electrons\nin a conjugated planar cyclic system that would make that system aromatic: 1) Four; 2) Five;\n3) Six.\n","spokenAnswer":"3\n","answer":"3\n","timer":5},{"question":"6) Energy – Multiple Choice - One of the most promising generation IV nuclear reactor designs involves\nthe use of supercritical water as the coolant. What is the main reason to use supercritical water?\nW) It has a higher neutron absorption cross section\nX) It has a lower neutron absorption cross section\nY) It is fissile\nZ) It allows for a higher thermal efficiency\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) IT ALLOWS FOR A HIGHER THERMAL EFFICIENCY\n","answer":"Z) IT ALLOWS FOR A HIGHER THERMAL EFFICIENCY\n","timer":20},{"question":"3) Energy – Multiple Choice - Lawrence Berkeley National Lab scientists are studying the teeth\nof parrotfish due to their unique structure. Parrotfish can be classified best as which of the\nfollowing?\nW) Lobe-finned fish\nX) Hagfish\nY) Ray-finned fish\nZ) Sharks\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) RAY-FINNED FISH\n","answer":"Y) RAY-FINNED FISH\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) ENERGY Short Answer - Assuming an equal concentration of each substance, by name or\nnumber, order the following four choices in terms of radiative forcing, from greatest to least: 1)\ncarbon dioxide, 2) methane, 3) fluorocarbons, 4) nitrous oxide.\n","spokenAnswer":"FLUOROCARBONS, NITROUS OXIDE, METHANE, CARBON DIOXIDE (ACCEPT:\n","answer":"FLUOROCARBONS, NITROUS OXIDE, METHANE, CARBON DIOXIDE (ACCEPT:\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) Math – Short Answer - A particle moves along a curve with equations x = 4cos t; y = 4sin t; z = 6t. What\nis the speed of the particle at time t = π/2?\n","spokenAnswer":"2 times the square root of 13\n","answer":"2 times the square root of 13\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Biology – Multiple Choice - Which of the following lengths of DNA would be least likely to\nbe unwound by a passive helicase?\nW) ATATAT\nX) AAATTT\nY) TTTGGG\nZ) GCGCGC\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) GCGCGC\n","answer":"Z) GCGCGC\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following assumptions is typically made\nwhen performing potassium-argon dating?\nW) Potassium-40 only decays into argon-40\nX) Some percentage of argon-40 produced by decay leaks out of the rock\nY) Potassium-40 has a half-life of 1.3 million years\nZ) All argon-40 in a rock was produced by potassium-40 decay\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) ALL ARGON-40 IN A ROCK WAS PRODUCED BY POTASSIUM-40\n","answer":"Z) ALL ARGON-40 IN A ROCK WAS PRODUCED BY POTASSIUM-40\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - What is the hybridization of the xenon atom in xenon\ntetrafluoride?\n","spokenAnswer":"sp3\n","answer":"sp3\n","timer":20},{"question":"6) MATH Multiple Choice - The sum of the squares of reciprocals of all positive integers equals\nwhich of the following?\nW) π\nX) π/3\nY) π2\n/6\nZ) π3\n/12\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) π2\n","answer":"Y) π2\n","timer":5},{"question":"4) Physics – Short Answer - A hollow pipe closed at both ends has a fundamental frequency of\n100 hertz. In meters, what is the length of the pipe?\n","spokenAnswer":"1.7\n","answer":"1.7\n","timer":20},{"question":"14) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Given the balanced chemical equation:\nH2SO4(aq) + 2NaOH(aq) → Na2SO4(aq) + 2H2O(l), in an acid-base titration, 25 milliliters of 0.2 molar\nH2SO4 were required to neutralize 100 milliliters of NaOH solution. Providing your answer as a\ndecimal to the nearest tenth, what is the molarity of the NaOH solution?\n","spokenAnswer":"0.1\n","answer":"0.1\n","timer":5},{"question":"1) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following events occurred in the Late Mississippian?\nW) Breakup of Rodinia\nX) Collision of Gondwana with Laurasia\nY) Collision of Laurentia with Baltica\nZ) Breakup of Pangaea\n","spokenAnswer":"X) COLLISION OF GONDWANA WITH LAURASIA\n","answer":"X) COLLISION OF GONDWANA WITH LAURASIA\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of Earth’s Milankovitch [mil-AYN-koh-vitch]\ncycles has a period of approximately one hundred thousand years?\nW) Axial tilt\nX) Precession\nY) Eccentricity\nZ) Obliquity\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) ECCENTRICITY\n","answer":"Y) ECCENTRICITY\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) Math – Short Answer - How many zeroes occur at the right of the number of permutations\nof 60 objects taken 20 at a time?\n","spokenAnswer":"5\n","answer":"5\n","timer":20},{"question":"11) Biology – Short Answer - Fruit ripening is promoted by which plant hormone?\n","spokenAnswer":"ETHYLENE (ACCEPT: ETHENE)\n","answer":"ETHYLENE (ACCEPT: ETHENE)\n","timer":5},{"question":"19) BIOLOGY Short Answer - By name or number, identify all of the following five interactions\nthat are typically interspecific and result in one species benefitting while the other is harmed: 1)\nmutualism, 2) amensalism, 3) parasitism, 4) commensalism, 5) herbivory.\n","spokenAnswer":"PARASITISM, HERBIVORY (ACCEPT: 3 AND 5)\n","answer":"PARASITISM, HERBIVORY (ACCEPT: 3 AND 5)\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - In preparing to perform a flame test on a sample, a high\nmolar solution of which of the following chemicals would be best to use to clean your nichrome\nwire?\nW) Sodium hydroxide\nX) Nitrous acid\nY) Hydrochloric acid\nZ) Lithium hydroxide\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) HYDROCHLORIC ACID\n","answer":"Y) HYDROCHLORIC ACID\n","timer":5},{"question":"2) Chemistry – Short Answer - What is the fewest number of carbonyl [carbon-EEL] stretching bands that can be seen\nin the infrared spectrum of a metal atom that is bound to four CO ligands [LIH-gunz]?\n","spokenAnswer":"1\n","answer":"1\n","timer":20},{"question":"23) Biology – Short Answer - If the sinoatrial [SIGH-no-AY-tree-ul] node fails, what tissue\nwill be responsible for setting the pace of the heart?\n","spokenAnswer":"AV NODE (ACCEPT: ATRIOVENTRICULAR NODE)\n","answer":"AV NODE (ACCEPT: ATRIOVENTRICULAR NODE)\n","timer":5},{"question":"21) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Assuming negligible air resistance, which of the following\nstatements is TRUE about two-dimensional projectile motion?\nW) The vertical motion is dependent on the horizontal motion\nX) The horizontal motion is dependent on the vertical motion\nY) The horizontal motion and vertical motion are both dependent on the projectile’s acceleration\nvector\nZ) The horizontal motion and vertical motion are independent of each other\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) THE HORIZONTAL MOTION AND VERTICAL MOTION ARE INDEPENDENT\n","answer":"Z) THE HORIZONTAL MOTION AND VERTICAL MOTION ARE INDEPENDENT\n","timer":20},{"question":"14) MATH Short Answer - What is the radius of the circle with equation\nx2 + 6x + y2 8y 11= 0?\n","spokenAnswer":"6\n","answer":"6\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) ENERGY Multiple Choice - FutureGen 2.0 power plants will reduce carbon dioxide production\nby burning coal in which of the following ways?\nW) With a mixture of oxygen and carbon dioxide instead of air to produce concentrated carbon\ndioxide\nX) With an enhanced concentration of oxygen instead of air to produce less carbon dioxide per\nton of coal burned\nY) In a catalytic chamber that scrubs the carbon dioxide out of the emissions\nZ) Using carbon dioxide reduced coal in an 80% nitrogen and 18% oxygen mixture\n","spokenAnswer":"W) WITH A MIXTURE OF OXYGEN AND CARBON DIOXIDE INSTEAD OF AIR TO \n","answer":"W) WITH A MIXTURE OF OXYGEN AND CARBON DIOXIDE INSTEAD OF AIR TO \n","timer":20},{"question":"6) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - What facial muscle functions to enable blinking?\nW) Zygomaticus [zy-guh-MA-ti-kuhs]\nX) Orbicularis oculi [or-bee-kyoo-LUH-ris]\nY) Orbicularis oris\nZ) Corrugator supercillii\n","spokenAnswer":"X) ORBICULARIS OCULI\n","answer":"X) ORBICULARIS OCULI\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) Biology – Short Answer - What is the name of the specific sugar that animal cells use as input into\nglycolysis?\n","spokenAnswer":"GLUCOSE\n","answer":"GLUCOSE\n","timer":20},{"question":"10) MATH Short Answer - Evaluate tan(sin-1(-1/2)) [tangent of the inverse sine of negative\none half].\n","spokenAnswer":"−√3\n","answer":"−√3\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What carbonate mineral is green in color and contains copper as its main cation?\n","spokenAnswer":"MALACHITE\n","answer":"MALACHITE\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) Energy – Multiple Choice - Scientists at SLAC [slack] recently demonstrated that coating the gold tip\nof an electron gun with nanodiamonds resulted in a higher electron flux through the gun. This is because the\ndiamonds changed what property of the electron gun tip?\nW) Conductance\nX) Electron density\nY) Voltage\nZ) Work function\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) WORK FUNCTION\n","answer":"Z) WORK FUNCTION\n","timer":5},{"question":"19) Earth and Space – Short Answer - Unlike reflectors, refracting telescopes may require an additional lens to correct\nfor what optical disturbance?\n","spokenAnswer":"CHROMATIC ABERRATION\n","answer":"CHROMATIC ABERRATION\n","timer":20},{"question":"6) Energy – Multiple Choice - Which of the following are characteristics of an ideal voltmeter?\nW) Infinitely large resistance and no potential difference between its terminals\nX) Infinitely large resistance and no current diverted through it\nY) Zero resistance and no potential difference between its terminals\nZ) Zero resistance and no current diverted through it\n","spokenAnswer":"X) INFINITELY LARGE RESISTANCE AND NO CURRENT DIVERTED THROUGH IT\n","answer":"X) INFINITELY LARGE RESISTANCE AND NO CURRENT DIVERTED THROUGH IT\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) Energy – Multiple Choice - The further advancement of rechargeable batteries is currently hindered by unavoidable\ngrowth of what during battery cell recharge?\nW) Lithium dendrites\nX) Potassium salts\nY) Nickel deposits\nZ) Lead precipitates\n","spokenAnswer":"W) LITHIUM DENDRITES\n","answer":"W) LITHIUM DENDRITES\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) Biology – Multiple Choice - The organisms that form arbuscular mycorrhizae are part of\nwhat group of fungi?\nW) Chytrids [KIH-trids]\nX) Glomeromycetes [glo-mair-oh-MY-seets]\nY) Basidiomycetes [bah-sid-ee-oh-MY-seet]\nZ) Ascomycetes\n","spokenAnswer":"X) GLOMEROMYCETES\n","answer":"X) GLOMEROMYCETES\n","timer":5},{"question":"1) Biology – Multiple Choice - The majority of speciation [spee-see-AY-shun] occurs under which of the following\ncircumstances?\nW) When populations undergo sexual selection\nX) When populations become geographically separated\nY) When populations are R selected\nZ) When populations reach carrying capacity\n","spokenAnswer":"X) WHEN POPULATIONS BECOME GEOGRAPHICALLY SEPARATED\n","answer":"X) WHEN POPULATIONS BECOME GEOGRAPHICALLY SEPARATED\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) PHYSICS Short Answer - Identify all of the following three experiments that demonstrate the\nparticle nature of light: 1) photoelectric effect; 2) dual-slit experiment; 3) Davisson-Germer\nexperiment.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 (ACCEPT: PHOTOELECTRIC EFFECT)\n","answer":"1 (ACCEPT: PHOTOELECTRIC EFFECT)\n","timer":5},{"question":"12) Math – Short Answer - Evaluate the following expression: –i 33.\n","spokenAnswer":"–i\n","answer":"–i\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) Math – Short Answer - What base-10 numeral does the following Roman numeral represent: CMXLVI?\n","spokenAnswer":"946\n","answer":"946\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following allotropes of phosphorous consists of chains of\ncovalently-linked P4 tetrahedra?\nW) White phosphorous\nX) Red phosphorous\nY) Black phosphorous\nZ) Violet phosphorous\n","spokenAnswer":"X) RED PHOSPHOROUS\n","answer":"X) RED PHOSPHOROUS\n","timer":20},{"question":"3) Physics – Short Answer - Consider the following dispersion relation: omega = 2k\n2 – 9k + 6.\nAt what two wavenumbers, k, are the group and phase velocity equal?\n","spokenAnswer":"SQUARE ROOT OF 3 and NEGATIVE SQUARE ROOT OF 3 (ACCEPT: PLUS\n","answer":"SQUARE ROOT OF 3 and NEGATIVE SQUARE ROOT OF 3 (ACCEPT: PLUS\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) Biology – Short Answer - If blood from an incompatible ABO group is mistakenly\ntransfused, it can agglutinate. What class of antibodies mediates this process?\n","spokenAnswer":"IgM (ACCEPT: M, IMMUNOGLOBULIN M)\n","answer":"IgM (ACCEPT: M, IMMUNOGLOBULIN M)\n","timer":20},{"question":"23) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Which of the following is the most accurate description of\ncharging by induction?\nW) It depends on putting two objects in actual physical contact with each other\nX) It depends on the use of friction\nY) It depends on the use of a ground to redistribute charges\nZ) It depends on gain of electrons during chemical reactions\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) IT DEPENDS ON THE USE OF A GROUND TO REDISTRIBUTE CHARGES\n","answer":"Y) IT DEPENDS ON THE USE OF A GROUND TO REDISTRIBUTE CHARGES\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - If bombarding a beryllium target by alpha particles produces a\nneutron, which of the following must also be produced?\nW) Lithium\nX) Boron\nY) Carbon\nZ) Nitrogen\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) CARBON\n","answer":"Y) CARBON\n","timer":20},{"question":"6) MATH Short Answer - Linear correlation coefficients must lie between what two values?\n","spokenAnswer":"-1 AND 1\n","answer":"-1 AND 1\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following drainage patterns would likely be visible\non jointed, rocky terrain?\nW) Dendritic [den-DRIH-dik]\nX) Trellis\nY) Radial\nZ) Rectangular\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) RECTANGULAR\n","answer":"Z) RECTANGULAR\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - A physical chemist has determined the vapor pressure of a liquid at\nmultiple temperatures and wants to determine the standard entropy of vaporization. Which of the following\nsets of axes will enable the chemist to graph the data as a line and determine the entropy from the\ny-intercept?\nW) Pressure on y, temperature on x\nX) One over pressure on y, temperature on x\nY) Natural log of pressure on y, temperature on x\nZ) Natural log of pressure on y, one over temperature on x\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) NATURAL LOG OF PRESSURE ON Y, ONE OVER TEMPERATURE ON X\n","answer":"Z) NATURAL LOG OF PRESSURE ON Y, ONE OVER TEMPERATURE ON X\n","timer":5},{"question":"9) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What is the empirical formula and charge of the silicon-oxygen\ntetrahedron, also known as the fundamental building block of all silicate materials?\n","spokenAnswer":"EMPIRICAL FORMULA: SiO4 , CHARGE: 4-\n","answer":"EMPIRICAL FORMULA: SiO4 , CHARGE: 4-\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - To identify the chemical compounds dissolved in a sample, a\nstudent dips a clean piece of nichrome wire into the sample and burns it in a flame. By name or\nnumber, identify all of the following five substances that might be present if the flame burns\nblue: 1) selenium, 2) sodium, 3) arsenic, 4) boron, 5) lead.\n","spokenAnswer":"SELENIUM, ARSENIC, LEAD (ACCEPT: 1, 3, 5)\n","answer":"SELENIUM, ARSENIC, LEAD (ACCEPT: 1, 3, 5)\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) Chemistry – Short Answer - Pourbaix [poor-BAY] diagrams show the most stable species\nin an aqueous electrolyte as a function of what two variables?\n","spokenAnswer":"pH AND POTENTIAL (ACCEPT: pH AND VOLTAGE)\n","answer":"pH AND POTENTIAL (ACCEPT: pH AND VOLTAGE)\n","timer":20},{"question":"6) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - The helium flash occurs in what stage of stellar\nevolution?\nW) Main sequence\nX) Subgiant branch\nY) Asymptotic giant branch\nZ) Tip of the red giant branch\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) TIP OF THE RED GIANT BRANCH\n","answer":"Z) TIP OF THE RED GIANT BRANCH\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) Energy – Multiple Choice - What country used 100% renewable energy for 75 consecutive\ndays in 2015?\nW) Lesotho [leh-SOH-toh]\nX) Costa Rica\nY) Norway\nZ) Sweden\n","spokenAnswer":"X) COSTA RICA\n","answer":"X) COSTA RICA\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) Earth and Space – Short Answer - A parcel of dry air has a temperature of 0° Celsius as it crosses a\nmountain range at 3 kilometers. If it descends adiabatically, what will its temperature be, rounded up to the\nnext whole Celsius degree, when it reaches sea level?\n","spokenAnswer":"30\n","answer":"30\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) ENERGY Multiple Choice - Power companies estimate the over-time cost of designing,\nbuilding, operating, and decommissioning a power plant in order to calculate which of the\nfollowing?\n\nW) Intrinsic cost\nX) Comprehensive fuel cost\nY) Levelized cost\nZ) Future-versus-present earnings\n\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) LEVELIZED COST\n","answer":"Y) LEVELIZED COST\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) ENERGY Short Answer - What functional unit in coal-based power production efficiently\nremoves particulate matter?\n","spokenAnswer":"ELECTROSTATIC PRECIPITATOR\n","answer":"ELECTROSTATIC PRECIPITATOR\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three organic acids that would be\nmore acidic in water than in acetic acid: 1) Chloroacetic acid; 2) Formic acid; 3) Propanoic acid.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 AND 2 (ACCEPT: CHLOROACETIC ACID AND FORMIC ACID)\n","answer":"1 AND 2 (ACCEPT: CHLOROACETIC ACID AND FORMIC ACID)\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) Physics – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true of Carnot engines: 1)\nCarnot’s Theorem limits the efficiency of engines to less than that of a Carnot engine; 2) The Carnot cycle\nconsists of only reversible steps; 3) The concept of entropy arose from the limits stated by the Carnot cycle.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 2, AND 3\n","answer":"1, 2, AND 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Under which of the following circumstances does\nocean depth affect ocean wave motion?\nW) When ocean depth falls below half the wavelength of a wave\nX) When the ocean wave has a period exceeding 20 seconds\nY) When the ocean waves are impacted by tides\nZ) When the ocean floor has high relief, regardless of the depth\n","spokenAnswer":"W) WHEN OCEAN DEPTH FALLS BELOW HALF THE WAVELENGTH OF A WAVE\n","answer":"W) WHEN OCEAN DEPTH FALLS BELOW HALF THE WAVELENGTH OF A WAVE\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) Math – Short Answer - For what integer value of k is 2015 cubed closest to 10k\n?\n","spokenAnswer":"10\n","answer":"10\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) Physics – Short Answer - A cannon fires several cannonballs at the same initial speed but at several\ndifferent angles, the furthest landing 100 meters away. What is the slowest possible speed, in meters per\nsecond and to the nearest ten, at which these cannonballs could have been fired?\n","spokenAnswer":"30\n","answer":"30\n","timer":20},{"question":"23) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What spectral class of stars possesses the strongest Balmer lines?\n","spokenAnswer":"A (ACCEPT: A-ZERO)\n","answer":"A (ACCEPT: A-ZERO)\n","timer":5},{"question":"21) PHYSICS Short Answer - A falling cat reaches a first terminal speed of 100 kilometers per\nhour while it is tucked in and then stretches out, doubling its effective cross-sectional area\nwithout changing its drag coefficient. Providing your answer to the nearest ten, how fast is it\nfalling in meters per second when it reaches a new terminal speed?\n","spokenAnswer":"70\n","answer":"70\n","timer":20},{"question":"11) Energy – Short Answer - Scientists at Pacific Northwest National Lab are studying cytokine\n[SIGH- toh-KINE] production during disease. Identify all of the following three statements that\nare true of cytokines: 1) They are peptides; 2) They are transcription factors and signal via\ndiffusing through the cell membrane; 3) They can be released by T cells.\n","spokenAnswer":"1, 3\n","answer":"1, 3\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) Chemistry – Short Answer - Andrew synthesizes a compound that consists of a benzene ring with an\nalcohol group in the one position and a primary amine in the four position. Identify all of the following\nthree names that unambiguously represent the structure of this compound: 1) P-aminophenol;\n2) 4-aminophenol; 3) 4-hydroxyaniline.\n","spokenAnswer":"ALL\n","answer":"ALL\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - The polymerization of a 1,3 diene [DY-een] will produce a\nmaterial that can be used to make which of the following polymers?\nW) Nylon\nX) Rubber\nY) Styrene\nZ) Thermoplastic\n","spokenAnswer":"X) RUBBER\n","answer":"X) RUBBER\n","timer":5},{"question":"4) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - Which two planets in our solar system have the highest\nfraction of methane in their atmospheres?\n","spokenAnswer":"NEPTUNE and URANUS \n","answer":"NEPTUNE and URANUS \n","timer":20},{"question":"15) Chemistry – Short Answer - What scientist, whose graduate students Geiger and Marsden\nperformed an experiment that involved shooting alpha particles at a metallic foil, was the first to\npropose that an atom consisted of a dense positively-charged nucleus with mobile electrons\nsurrounding the nucleus?\n","spokenAnswer":"ERNEST RUTHERFORD (ACCEPT: RUTHERFORD)\n","answer":"ERNEST RUTHERFORD (ACCEPT: RUTHERFORD)\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Stress-strain curves show how real materials respond to forces\nthat are applied to them. Materials such as steel have a region of elasticity where they\napproximate an ideal spring and a region where they start to deform plastically. Where the\nmaterials are acting like an ideal spring, how do we find their Young\n's modulus?\nW) It is the slope of the stress-strain curve\nX) It is the integral of the curve in the elastic region\nY) It is the y-intercept of the stress-strain curve\nZ) It is the second derivative of the curve just after transition into the region of plastic\ndeformation\n","spokenAnswer":"W) IT IS THE SLOPE OF THE STRESS-STRAIN CURVE\n","answer":"W) IT IS THE SLOPE OF THE STRESS-STRAIN CURVE\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) Math – Multiple Choice - Consider the graph of the function 4x2 – 4y2 = 0. Which of the following shapes\nmost resembles the graph of this function?\nW) Circle\nX) Hyperbola\nY) Pair of intersecting straight lines\nZ) Ellipse\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) PAIR OF INTERSECTING STRAIGHT LINES\n","answer":"Y) PAIR OF INTERSECTING STRAIGHT LINES\n","timer":5},{"question":"18) Math – Short Answer - A 5-digit palindrome has 3 different digits and is divisible by 18. What is its largest possible\nvalue?\n","spokenAnswer":"89,298\n","answer":"89,298\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) PHYSICS Short Answer - Air resistance is a function of the effective cross sectional area of\nthe body, the drag coefficient, and what other two variables?\n","spokenAnswer":"AIR DENSITY AND VELOCITY\n","answer":"AIR DENSITY AND VELOCITY\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Which of the following laws or principles gives a physical\ninterpretation for the sign convention used in Faraday’s law of induction?\nW) Lenz’s law\nX) Ampere’s law\nY) Coulomb’s law\nZ) Gauss’s law\n","spokenAnswer":"W) LENZ’S LAW\n","answer":"W) LENZ’S LAW\n","timer":20},{"question":"13) ENERGY Short Answer - What is the electrode material of choice for capacitive deionization\nof seawater?\n","spokenAnswer":"CARBON\n","answer":"CARBON\n","timer":5},{"question":"3) CHEMISTRY Multiple Choice - In which of the following scattering angles is Rayleigh [RAYlee] scattering from unpolarized light the most intense?\nW) 0°\nX) 45°\nY) 90°\nZ) 180°\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) 90°\n","answer":"Y) 90°\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) ENERGY Short Answer - What is the name of the technique used to enrich gaseous U-235\nafter it has been combined with fluorine?\n","spokenAnswer":"CENTRIFUGATION \n","answer":"CENTRIFUGATION \n","timer":5},{"question":"16) Energy – Multiple Choice - What biological carbon sequestration method uses iron and\nrequires a better understanding of iron cycling in marine systems to determine its long-term\nimpacts?\nW) Iron geo-reduction\nX) Iron sequestration\nY) Iron filtering\nZ) Iron fertilization\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) IRON FERTILIZATION\n","answer":"Z) IRON FERTILIZATION\n","timer":20},{"question":"20) Chemistry – Short Answer - Within a valence bond interpretation, what is the hybridization of the carbon atoms’\nvalence electrons in the ethylene molecule?\n","spokenAnswer":"SP2\n","answer":"SP2\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - A 2.00 mole sample of ammonium nitrate is decomposed in a\nbomb calorimeter. The temperature of the calorimeter increases by 12 Kelvin. The heat capacity\nof the system is 1.5 kilojoules per Kelvin. What is the molar heat of decomposition of ammonium\nnitrate in kilojoules?\n","spokenAnswer":"9\n","answer":"9\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Water flows at 2.0 meters per second through a tube of radius 1\ncentimeter. The dynamic viscosity of the water is 1.0 × 10-3 pascal seconds. Which of the\nfollowing best represents the Reynolds number and the nature of the flow, given that the density\nof water is 1.0 × 103 kilograms per cubic meter?\nW) 40,000; turbulent\nX) 40,000; laminar\nY) 20,000; turbulent\nZ) 20,000; laminar\n","spokenAnswer":"W) 40,000; TURBULENT\n","answer":"W) 40,000; TURBULENT\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) BIOLOGY Short Answer - What fluid, produced by ependymal cells, fills the space between\nthe arachnoid [uh-RAK-noid] and the pia mater as well as the ventricles of the brain?\n","spokenAnswer":"CEREBROSPINAL FLUID\n","answer":"CEREBROSPINAL FLUID\n","timer":20},{"question":"9) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - Which of the following best represents a closed system?\nW) A 2-liter bottle filled with aquatic plants, a fish, water, and a bit of air, sealed with a tight lid\nand placed in a window\nX) A terrarium with a closed lid, some plants, and a live boa constrictor\nY) The Earth\nZ) The universe\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) THE UNIVERSE\n","answer":"Z) THE UNIVERSE\n","timer":5},{"question":"14) Physics – Short Answer - The position of a particle in meters is described by the function x\nof t equals t cubed plus 4 t squared plus 3 t, where t is expressed in seconds. What is the\nacceleration, in meters per second squared, at time t equals 5?\n","spokenAnswer":"38\n","answer":"38\n","timer":20},{"question":"23) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - There is an electrostatic force of attraction between any two of\nthree metal spheres P, Q, and R. Which of the following is a possible combination for the\ncharges on P, Q, and R?\nW) P: positive, Q: negative, R: positive\nX) P: positive, Q: negative, R: neutral\nY) P: positive, Q: positive, R: positive\nZ) P: neutral, Q: positive, R: neutral\n","spokenAnswer":"X) P: POSITIVE, Q: NEGATIVE, R: NEUTRAL\n","answer":"X) P: POSITIVE, Q: NEGATIVE, R: NEUTRAL\n","timer":5},{"question":"24) ENERGY Short Answer - By name or number, order the following processes from first to last\nin a gas turbine operating under an actual Brayton cycle: 1) heat rejection, 2) expansion, 3) heat\naddition, 4) compression.\n","spokenAnswer":"COMPRESSION, HEAT ADDITION, EXPANSION, HEAT REJECTION (ACCEPT:\n","answer":"COMPRESSION, HEAT ADDITION, EXPANSION, HEAT REJECTION (ACCEPT:\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What type of sub-stellar object can fuse\ndeuterium [doo-TEER-ee-um] but not hydrogen?\n","spokenAnswer":"BROWN DWARF\n","answer":"BROWN DWARF\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) Physics – Short Answer - In terms of the elementary charge e, what is the electric charge of an up\nquark?\n","spokenAnswer":"POSITIVE (2/3)e (ACCEPT: (2/3)e, 2e/3)\n","answer":"POSITIVE (2/3)e (ACCEPT: (2/3)e, 2e/3)\n","timer":20},{"question":"6) MATH Short Answer - Evaluate [the integral from the square root of 2\nto the 3 times the square root of 2 of the quantity 3 x squared plus 6 dx] in simplest radical\nform.\n","spokenAnswer":"\n","answer":"\n","timer":5},{"question":"4) Physics – Multiple Choice - Planck resolved the ultraviolet catastrophe for black bodies by postulating\nthe quantization of photon energies to derive an expression showing that the modal energies obey which of\nthe following statistical distributions?\nW) Fermi-Dirac\nX) Maxwell-Boltzmann\nY) Bose-Einstein\nZ) Gaussian\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) BOSE-EINSTEIN\n","answer":"Y) BOSE-EINSTEIN\n","timer":20},{"question":"8) Chemistry – Short Answer - What process, whose first oxidative step is catalyzed in the\natmosphere by dust grains and industrially by vanadium pentoxide, generates oleum, which is\nreacted with water to make sulfuric acid?\n","spokenAnswer":"CONTACT PROCESS\n","answer":"CONTACT PROCESS\n","timer":5},{"question":"22) PHYSICS Short Answer - By number rank the following three systems of materials, from\nlowest to highest, in terms of their coefficients of kinetic friction: 1) rubber on concrete; 2) human\njoints; 3) ice on ice.\n","spokenAnswer":"2, 3, 1\n","answer":"2, 3, 1\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) PHYSICS Short Answer - A food shipper pushes a wooden crate of lettuce with a total mass\nof 14 kilograms across a concrete floor with a constant horizontal force of magnitude 40\nnewtons. In a straight-line displacement of magnitude 0.50 meters, the speed of the crate\ndecreases from 0.60 meters per second to 0.20 meters per second. How much work, in joules,\nis done by the horizontal force?\n","spokenAnswer":"20\n","answer":"20\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - In Long Island’s Peconic Bays, a bloom of small\nmarine algae called Aureococcus anophagefferens (read as: ohr-ee-oh- KOH-kuhs ah-noh-fahgeh-FEH-rehns) turned the water a deep brown. By name or number, identify all of the following\nfour organisms that were physically harmed by this brown tide: 1) scallops, 2) eelgrass, 3)\nhumans, 4) mussels.\n","spokenAnswer":"SCALLOPS, EELGRASS, MUSSELS (ACCEPT: 1, 2, 4)\n","answer":"SCALLOPS, EELGRASS, MUSSELS (ACCEPT: 1, 2, 4)\n","timer":20},{"question":"1) PHYSICS Multiple Choice - A 1000-watt oven is connected to a 240-volt AC power source.\nWhich of the following is nearest the peak voltage across the oven?\nW) 120\nX) 270\nY) 340\nZ) 370\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) 340\n","answer":"Y) 340\n","timer":5},{"question":"16) MATH Short Answer - What is the area, in square meters, of a triangle whose sides are of\nlength 10, 12, and 14 meters?\n","spokenAnswer":"24√6\n","answer":"24√6\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) Physics – Short Answer - If an electron is moving in the positive-x direction with increasing speed, identify all of the\nfollowing three scenarios that could be responsible for the driving force: 1) A magnetic field pointing in the negative-x\ndirection; 2) An electric field pointing in the negative-x direction; 3) A magnetic field pointing in the negative-z direction.\n","spokenAnswer":"2\n","answer":"2\n","timer":5},{"question":"15) BIOLOGY Short Answer - By number, order the following four steps from earliest to latest in\nan action potential: 1) sodium channel inactivation gates close and gated potassium channels\nopen; 2) leak potassium channels are open and all gated channels are closed; 3) activation\ngates of some sodium channels open; 4) voltage gated sodium activation channels open.\n","spokenAnswer":"2, 3, 4, 1\n","answer":"2, 3, 4, 1\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) PHYSICS Short Answer - When an object with a volume of 10 cubic meters is completely\nsubmerged in water, given that acceleration due to gravity is 9.8 meters per second squared,\nwhat is the buoyant force on the object in newtons if the density of water is 1000 kilograms per\ncubic meter?\n","spokenAnswer":"98,000\n","answer":"98,000\n","timer":5},{"question":"12) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three statements that are true of\nbonding: 1) Xenon dichloride has a bent molecular geometry; 2) Sulfur dioxide and carbon\ndisulfide have the same molecular geometry; 3) Krypton tetrafluoride has no net dipole moment.\n","spokenAnswer":"3\n","answer":"3\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) Physics – Short Answer - Consider the set of quantum numbers, -1, 0, and 1. Which one or ones could be\nfound in a hydrogen atom wave function in which the principle quantum number is equal to 2 and the orbital\nor angular momentum quantum number is equal to 1?\n","spokenAnswer":"-1, 0, 1\n","answer":"-1, 0, 1\n","timer":5},{"question":"12) ENERGY Short Answer - Assume we have two inlets to a hydroelectric plant’s turbines: one\ninlet is at 50 m depth, and the second inlet is at 80 m depth. How much greater, by percentage,\nis the pressure at the deeper compared to the shallower one?\n","spokenAnswer":"60% GREATER (ACCEPT: 60%)\n","answer":"60% GREATER (ACCEPT: 60%)\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) Energy – Multiple Choice - Which of the following would not be considered a balance-ofsystem component for a stand-alone wind power system?\nW) Battery\nX) Circuit breaker\nY) Inverter\nZ) Turbine\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) TURBINE\n","answer":"Z) TURBINE\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - Which of the following features is NOT associated\nwith subduction zone geology?\nW) San Joaquin Valley, California\nX) Accreted terrains of coastal California\nY) North Carolina barrier islands\nZ) Cascade Mountains in Oregon and Washington\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) NORTH CAROLINA BARRIER ISLANDS\n","answer":"Y) NORTH CAROLINA BARRIER ISLANDS\n","timer":20},{"question":"5) Biology – Short Answer - What iron-containing proteins are the main enzymes associated\nwith the metabolism of drugs and toxins in the liver?\n","spokenAnswer":"CYTOCHROME P450 (ACCEPT: CYP)\n","answer":"CYTOCHROME P450 (ACCEPT: CYP)\n","timer":5},{"question":"17) MATH Short Answer - Each of the following equations represents a plane: x – y = 6;\n2x – 3z = 16; 2y + z = 4. At which point (x, y, z), will they intersect?\n","spokenAnswer":"(8, 2, 0)\n","answer":"(8, 2, 0)\n","timer":20},{"question":"4) Chemistry – Short Answer - Nitrogen monoxide decomposes into diatomic nitrogen and oxygen at high\ntemperatures. A one-liter reaction vessel at 2000°C contains an equilibrium mixture of 192 grams of O2, 112\ngrams of N2, and 3 grams of NO. Using values of 14 grams per mole and 16 grams per mole for the\nrespective molar masses of atomic nitrogen and oxygen, what is the equilibrium constant for the\ndecomposition at this temperature to two significant figures?\n","spokenAnswer":"2.4x103 (ACCEPT 2400)\n","answer":"2.4x103 (ACCEPT 2400)\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) BIOLOGY Short Answer - An F1 individual is heterozygous for each of 4 traits, A, B, C, and\nD, and is allowed to self-fertilize. What is the probability that the offspring will be AaBBccDd?\n","spokenAnswer":"1/64\n","answer":"1/64\n","timer":20},{"question":"16) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - Which of the following is the molecular orbital theory prediction for the\nbond order of the dioxygenyl radical cation, whose chemical formula is O2+?\nW) 1\nX) 1.5\nY) 2\nZ) 2.5\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) 2.5\n","answer":"Z) 2.5\n","timer":5},{"question":"8) Biology – Multiple Choice - A patient is demonstrating loss in bone density. Which of the following\nhormones would be most useful in treating this symptom?\nW) Parathyroid hormone\nX) Vasopressin\nY) Calcitonin [kal-sih-TOE-nin]\nZ) Mineralocorticoid [mineralo-CORE-deh-KOYD]\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) CALCITONIN\n","answer":"Y) CALCITONIN\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) Biology – Short Answer - Cytochrome proteins contain prosthetic groups that possess what\nmetal center?\n","spokenAnswer":"IRON\n","answer":"IRON\n","timer":5},{"question":"21) Physics – Short Answer - As the number of degrees of freedom of motion of an ideal gas\nincreases, what does its adiabatic [ad-ee-ah-BAT-ik] index asymptotically [ay-sim-TOT-ik-lee]\ntend to?\n","spokenAnswer":"ONE\n","answer":"ONE\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Physics – Multiple Choice - When Faraday was investigating the conductive properties of gases, he\nsealed metal electrodes into a glass tube and attached an electrostatic generator. When he started the\ngenerator, he noticed a purple glow. The purple color was dependant on which of the following?\nW) The conductivity of the gas in the tube\nX) The type of gas in the tube\nY) The type of metal used for the electrodes\nZ) The amount of energy given to the electrodes\n","spokenAnswer":"X) THE TYPE OF GAS IN THE TUBE\n","answer":"X) THE TYPE OF GAS IN THE TUBE\n","timer":5},{"question":"11) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - A reaction between two solutions A and B has a rate constant\nk of 1. If A increases from 2.0 molar to 4.0 molar and B is held constant, the reaction rate is\ndoubled. If B goes from 2.0 molar to 4.0 molar and A is held constant, the reaction rate is\nquadrupled. What is the overall reaction order?\n","spokenAnswer":"3 (ACCEPT: THIRD)\n","answer":"3 (ACCEPT: THIRD)\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Physics – Short Answer - What boson mediates the strong force?\n","spokenAnswer":"GLUON\n","answer":"GLUON\n","timer":5},{"question":"19) Chemistry – Short Answer - Rank the following three solid structures from the one with the\nlowest coordination number to the one with the highest: 1) Body-centered cubic; 2) Hexagonal\nclosest-packed; 3) Simple cubic.\n","spokenAnswer":"3, 1, 2 (ACCEPT: SIMPLE CUBIC, BODY-CENTERED CUBIC, HEXAGONAL\n","answer":"3, 1, 2 (ACCEPT: SIMPLE CUBIC, BODY-CENTERED CUBIC, HEXAGONAL\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) Chemistry – Multiple Choice - The precipitation reaction caused by the addition of potassium chloride\nto aqueous [AY-kwee-us] silver nitrate is an example of which of the following types of reactions?\nW) Metathesis [meh-TATH-uh-sis]\nX) Decomposition\nY) Synthesis\nZ) Redox\n","spokenAnswer":"W) METATHESIS\n","answer":"W) METATHESIS\n","timer":5},{"question":"7) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - Which of the following geologic phenomena led to the\nformation of submarine canyons?\nW) Bioturbation\nX) Tsunamis\nY) Turbidity currents\nZ) Volcanic eruptions\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) TURBIDITY CURRENTS\n","answer":"Y) TURBIDITY CURRENTS\n","timer":20},{"question":"7) BIOLOGY Short Answer - What genus of bacteria uses horizontal gene transfer to cause\ntumors in plants?\n","spokenAnswer":"AGROBACTERIUM\n","answer":"AGROBACTERIUM\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) PHYSICS Short Answer - Providing your answer in scientific notation with one significant\ndigit, calculate the de Broglie wavelength, in meters, of a car with a mass of 1600 kilograms\ntraveling at a speed of 40 meters per second.\n","spokenAnswer":"1 × 10−\n","answer":"1 × 10−\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) Math – Short Answer - For the arithmetic sequence with first term 2 and fifth term 22, what\nis the sum of the first 60 terms?\n","spokenAnswer":"8970\n","answer":"8970\n","timer":5},{"question":"6) EARTH AND SPACE Short Answer - The spectral lines of stars have a finite width. What are\nthe two phenomena responsible for this observation?\n","spokenAnswer":"DOPPLER EFFECT (ACCEPT: DOPPLER SHIFT OR DOPPLER BROADENING)\n","answer":"DOPPLER EFFECT (ACCEPT: DOPPLER SHIFT OR DOPPLER BROADENING)\n","timer":20},{"question":"17) Earth and Space – Multiple Choice - In which of the following locations would histosols\nmost likely be found?\nW) Desert\nX) Peat bog\nY) Boreal [BOAR-ee-ul] forest\nZ) Subhumid climate\n","spokenAnswer":"X) PEAT BOG\n","answer":"X) PEAT BOG\n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Math – Short Answer - What are the coordinates of the image of the point (–1, 4) when it is rotated\nabout the point (3, 2) by 90 degrees counterclockwise?\n","spokenAnswer":"(1, –2) (ACCEPT: x = 1 AND y = –2)\n","answer":"(1, –2) (ACCEPT: x = 1 AND y = –2)\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - Tunicamycin [too-ni-kuh-MY-sin] is a drug produced by some\nbacteria. It is used as a tool by molecular biologists because it induces eukaryotic [yoo-KARee-oh-tik] cells to arrest at the G1 checkpoint of the cell cycle. Using this information about\ntunicamycin and your knowledge of the cell cycle, which of the following would you expect to\nobserve in a tunicamycin-arrested cell?\nW) Activated APC protein\nX) Chiasmata [ky-AZ-muh-tuh]\nY) Replication bubbles\nZ) Spindle fibers\n","spokenAnswer":"W) ACTIVATED APC PROTEIN \n","answer":"W) ACTIVATED APC PROTEIN \n","timer":5},{"question":"18) Earth and Space – Short Answer - What allotrope of carbon is known for its strong bonds\nwithin the plane, but weak bonds between planes?\n","spokenAnswer":"GRAPHITE (DO NOT ACCEPT: GRAPHENE)\n","answer":"GRAPHITE (DO NOT ACCEPT: GRAPHENE)\n","timer":20},{"question":"2) Chemistry – Short Answer - Identify all of the following three molecules that typically\nundergo an Sn1 reaction in the presence of a nucleophile: 1) Methyl-bromide;\n2) 2-bromo-propane; 3) Tert-butyl-amine [turt-BYOO-til-ah-MEEN].\n","spokenAnswer":"2\n","answer":"2\n","timer":5},{"question":"13) CHEMISTRY Short Answer - Identify all of the following four types of reactions that follow\nZaitsev’s rule: 1) SN1; 2) SN2; 3) E1; 4) E2\n","spokenAnswer":"3 and 4 (ACCEPT: E1 and E2)\n","answer":"3 and 4 (ACCEPT: E1 and E2)\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - The toxin from the death cap mushroom is alpha-amanitin. This\ntoxin primarily binds and inhibits RNA polymerase [POL-uh-muh-rays] II. Transcription of which\nof the following types of RNA would be most impacted by poisoning with alpha-amanitin?\nW) siRNA\nX) mRNA\nY) rRNA\nZ) tRNA\n","spokenAnswer":"X) mRNA \n","answer":"X) mRNA \n","timer":5},{"question":"20) Math – Short Answer - If a, b, and c are the three zeroes of the polynomial\nx3 – 9x2 + 26x – 24, what is the product of the three numbers 1 – a, 1 – b, and 1 – c?\n","spokenAnswer":"–6\n","answer":"–6\n","timer":20},{"question":"19) BIOLOGY Multiple Choice - During starvation, muscles convert most of the amino acids\nreleased from muscle breakdown to what two specific amino acids for use in gluconeogenesis\n[gloo-koh-nee-uh-JEN-uh-sis]?\nW) Arginine and glycine [AHR-juh-neen]\nX) Arginine and glutamine\nY) Alanine and glutamine\nZ) Glutamine and glycine [GLY-seen]\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) ALANINE AND GLUTAMINE\n","answer":"Y) ALANINE AND GLUTAMINE\n","timer":5},{"question":"23) PHYSICS Short Answer - What type of antineutrino [an-tee-noo-TREE-noh] is produced in\nbeta decay?\n","spokenAnswer":"ELECTRON ANTINEUTRINO\n","answer":"ELECTRON ANTINEUTRINO\n","timer":20},{"question":"12) Math – Short Answer - A triangular right prism has each edge of length 4. What is its surface area?\n","spokenAnswer":"48 + 8√3 (ACCEPT: 8√3 + 48)\n","answer":"48 + 8√3 (ACCEPT: 8√3 + 48)\n","timer":5},{"question":"10) Math – Short Answer - f of x is a twice-differentiable function such that f prime of x and\nf double prime of x are both less than 0 for all real numbers. If f of 3 equals 22 and f of 5 equals\n17, what is the largest possible integer value for f of 9?\n","spokenAnswer":"6\n","answer":"6\n","timer":20},{"question":"18) EARTH AND SPACE Multiple Choice - A galaxy shows a strong bar and very loosely-wound\nspiral arms. Which of the following would most likely be its class?\nW) S0\nX) SBa\nY) SBc\nZ) Sb\n","spokenAnswer":"Y) SBc\n","answer":"Y) SBc\n","timer":5},{"question":"6) Energy – Multiple Choice - Scientists at Lawrence Berkeley National Lab recently captured images of a\nType one-A supernova in a galaxy four billion light-years away that appeared 50 times brighter than normal\nand in four different places in the sky. Which of the following did the scientists discover?\nW) A Type-one-A supernova with a progenitor that was 20-50 times more massive than normal\nX) An anomalous type-two supernova with a light curve resembling type Ia\nY) A light echo of a type-one-A supernova\nZ) A type-one-A supernova whose image was strongly gravitationally lensed\n","spokenAnswer":"Z) A TYPE-ONE-A SUPERNOVA WHOSE IMAGE WAS STRONGLY GRAVITATIONALLY\n","answer":"Z) A TYPE-ONE-A SUPERNOVA WHOSE IMAGE WAS STRONGLY GRAVITATIONALLY\n","timer":20},{"question":"21) Biology – Short Answer - What is the term for small, circular RNA molecules that can\ninfect plants?\n","spokenAnswer":"VIROIDS\n","answer":"VIROIDS\n","timer":5},{"question":"5) MATH Short Answer - Find the open intervals over which a function whose derivative is\n5x2(x + 5)(x − 3) [5 x squared times open parenthesis x plus 5 close parenthesis times the\nquantity x minus 3] is increasing.\n","spokenAnswer":"(−∞, −5) AND (3, ∞)\n","answer":"(−∞, −5) AND (3, ∞)\n","timer":20},{"question":"22) Biology – Multiple Choice - Which of the following immune cells is most involved in\ndefense against parasites?\nW) Neutrophils\nX) Eosinophils [ee-oh-SIN-oh-filz]\nY) Basophils [BAY-zoh-filz]\nZ) Mast cells\n","spokenAnswer":"X) EOSINOPHILS \n","answer":"X) EOSINOPHILS \n","timer":5},{"question":"7) Math – Short Answer - How many different sequences of 26 coin tosses result in at least 25 ‘heads’?\n","spokenAnswer":"27\n","answer":"27\n","timer":20}]